<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE tmx SYSTEM "tmx11.dtd">
<tmx version="1.1">
  <header creationtool="OmegaT" o-tmf="OmegaT TMX" adminlang="EN-US" datatype="plaintext" creationtoolversion="4.3.2_0_6a661c5e" segtype="paragraph" srclang="ZH-CN"/>
  <body>
<!-- Default translations -->
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>===第一章 惊蛰===</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T075934Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T073925Z">
        <seg>Chapter 1: Awakening</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>===第七章 碗水===</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T091048Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T091048Z">
        <seg>Chapter 7: </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>===第三章 日出===</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T172701Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T172701Z">
        <seg>Chapter 3: Sunrise</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>===第二章 开门===</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T112301Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T112301Z">
        <seg>Chapter 2: Open the Door</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>===第五章 道破===</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T231206Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T210336Z">
        <seg>Chapter 5: Revelation</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>===第六章 下签===</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T091030Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T231152Z">
        <seg>Chapter 6: Bad Slip </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>===第四章 黄鸟===</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021107Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T021030Z">
        <seg>Chapter 4: Oriole</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>“黄雀始欲衔花来，君家种桃花未开。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T014706Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T014706Z">
        <seg>"The oriole wishes to pluck a flower, but the peach blossoms are still yet to bloom."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>一个乡塾逃学的青衫少年，与陈平安擦肩而过。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230855Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T230855Z">
        <seg>An azure-robed young boy that was flunking his lessons at the private school passed by Chen Ping'an, and unbeknownst to him, a locust leaf had landed on his shoulder.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>一朴素道士，一寒酸少年，两个大小穷光蛋，相对而坐。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T011642Z">
        <seg>Thus, a modest taoist priest and an impoverished young man found themselves seated across from one another, each of them just as poor as the other.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>一直保持那个姿势的刘羡阳冷哼道：“你当真不明白？为什么你帮王朱那丫头提了一次水桶，那之后她就再也不跟你聊天说话了？保准是宋集薪那个小肚鸡肠的，打翻醋瓶子，就威胁王朱不许跟你眉来眼去，要不然就要家法伺候，不但打断她的腿，还要丢到泥瓶巷子里”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T113027Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T113027Z">
        <seg>Liu Xianyang was still supporting the entirety of his own weight with his hands, and he harrumphed coldly as he continued, "Do you really not understand? Why is that Wang Zhu never spoke to you again after you helped her carry her water bucket that one time? It's definitely because that petty little Song brat became jealous and threatened Wang Zhu with violence if she ever spoke to you again. I bet he told her that not only was he going to break his legs, he was also going to throw her onto Clay Vase Alley."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>一老一小缓缓走向那口铁锁井，小家伙，是个还挂着两条鼻涕虫的孩子，可是说起这个故事来，口齿清晰，有条不紊，根本不像是个才蒙学半年的乡野小娃娃，此时孩子正仰起头，大大的眼睛，像两颗黑葡萄，轻轻抽了抽鼻子，两条鼻涕小蛇就缩回去，孩子望着那个一手托着大白碗的说书先生，努努嘴，说道：“我说完了，你也该给我看看你碗里装着啥了吧？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T092459Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T092459Z">
        <seg>An old man and a small child were slowly making their way toward the Iron Lock Well. The child was still very young, with two lines of snot trailing out of his nostrils, but he could tell a very coherent and organized story, completely unlike the average rural child who had only been attending school for half a year. At this moment, the child was looking up with a pair of large eyes that resembled black grapes, and with a gentle sniffle, the two lines of snot retreated back into his nostrils. The child was looking at the storyteller who was carrying the large white bowl, and he said, "That's the end of my story. You're going to show me what's in your bowl now, right?"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>一袭青衫的高大男人接过信封后，温声说道：“以后无事的时候，你可以多来这里旁听。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T020721Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T020721Z">
        <seg>The man accepted the letter, then encouraged in a warm voice, "If you have some free time, you can come here and listen to my lessons."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>不凑巧，陈平安今天要送的十封信，几乎全是小镇出了名的阔绰户，这也很合情合理，龙生龙凤生凤，老鼠生儿打地洞，能够寄信回家的远方游子，家世肯定不差，否则也没那底气出门远行。其中九封信，陈平安其实就去了两个地方，福鹿街和桃叶巷，当他第一次踩在大如床板的青石板上，少年有些忐忑，放缓了脚步，竟然有些自惭形秽，忍不住觉得自己的草鞋脏了街面。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T175420Z">
        <seg>Coincidentally, almost all of the 10 letters that Chen Ping'an had been tasked with delivering were addressed to the renowned affluent families in the town. However, this was quite a reasonable occurrence. As the saying went, the offspring of dragons and phoenixes were destined to soar in the heavens, while the offspring of mice could burrow in the dirt. Those who were traveling far away and able to send letters back to their families had to have come from privileged backgrounds. Otherwise, they wouldn't have had the courage and financial backing to go to such faraway places. For nine of the 10 letters, Chen Ping'an only had to go to two places, namely Fortune Deer Street and Peach Leaf Alley. The bluestone slabs that paved these streets were as large as bedsteads, and he felt rather uneasy as he stepped onto them for the first time. He unconsciously slowed down in his footsteps, and he was struck by a sense of inferiority, feeling as if he were soiling the ground with his straw sandals.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>不是羡慕刘羡阳天赋高，力气大，人缘好。只是羡慕刘羡阳的天不怕地不怕，走到哪里都没心没肺，也从来不觉得独自活着，是什么糟糕的事情。刘羡阳不管到了什么地方，跟谁相处，很快就能够勾肩搭背，称兄道弟，喝酒划拳。刘羡阳因为他爷爷身体不好，很早就自力更生，成为孩子王一般的存在，捕蛇捉鱼掏鸟窝，无不娴熟，木弓鱼竿，弹弓捕鸟笼，刘羡阳好像什么都会做，尤其是在乡间田埂抓泥鳅和钓黄鳝这两件事，少年无疑是小镇上最厉害的。其实刘羡阳当年从乡塾退学的时候，那位齐先生还特意去找了刘羡阳病榻上的爷爷，说可以不收一钱，但是刘羡阳死活不答应，说他只想挣钱，不想读书，齐先生说他可以出钱雇佣刘阳羡当自己书童，刘羡阳依然不肯点头。事实上，刘羡阳活得挺好，哪怕姚老头死了，龙窑被封禁，没过几天他就被骑龙巷的铁匠相中，在小镇南边开始搭建茅屋、炉子，忙碌得很。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T073736Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T044117Z">
        <seg>He didn't envy Liu Xianyang for his remarkable aptitude, strength, and charisma. Instead, he envied Liu Xianyang's fearlessness. No matter where he went, Liu Xianyang was never fazed by anything, nor did he ever feel like living alone was a bad thing. Wherever he went, he was always able to quickly make friends with whoever he met, getting on such friendly terms with them that they referred to one another as brothers and would drink and play drinking games together. Due to his grandfather's ill health, Liu Xianyang was forced to become self-dependent from a very young age, making him a leader of sorts among the children in the area. He was skilled at everything, whether it be catching snakes, fishing, procuring eggs from bird's nests, making bows, fishing rods, slingshots, bird cages... It seemed like there was nothing that he couldn't do. In particular, he was the undisputed king of the town when it came to catching catfish and fishing for eels in the channels of water running through plots of farmland. Back when Liu Xianyang dropped out of the private school, the teacher there, Mr. Xu, had paid a visit to Liu Xianyang's grandfather on his sickbed, offering to Liu Xianyang an education free of charge. However, Liu Xianyang refused to go back no matter what, telling the teacher that all he wanted to do was earn money, and that he had no interest in an education. Mr. Xu then offered Liu Xianyang a paid job as a scholarly attendant, but Liu Xianyang turned down that offer as well. As it turned out, Liu Xianyang was doing quite well for himself. Even though Old Man Yao had passed away and the dragon kilns had been shut down, it didn't take long before he caught the eye of the blacksmith from Dragon Rider Alley, and he was currently busy building his own forge in the southern part of the town.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>不知不觉已经沦为弃子的邻居少年，日子倒是依旧过得优哉游哉，成天带着他的贴身丫鬟，在小镇内外逛荡，一年到头游手好闲，也从来不曾为银子发过愁。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T100037Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T100037Z">
        <seg>Unbeknownst to the young boy, he had been completely abandoned, and he continued to live a carefree and leisurely life, constantly wandering the town with his personal maidservant, never having to worry about money even though he didn't do a day of work throughout the year.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>不知何时，婢女稚圭已经从竹林折返，只是站在柴门外，并不踏足院子。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T082719Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T082719Z">
        <seg>At some point, Zhi Gui had already returned from the bamboo forest, but she was standing outside the wooden door, refraining from stepping into the yard.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>不管如何，婢女被少年取名为稚圭后，算是彻底坐实了两人的父子关系，因为小镇大族豪绅都晓得，宋大人最钟情于一方砚台，便刻有“稚圭”二字。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T224154Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T224049Z">
        <seg>In any case, after the maidservent was named Zhi Gui by Song Jixin, the father and son relationship between Song Jixin and Master Song was confirmed beyond a doubt. This was because all of the most affluent individuals in the town knew that the characters "Zhi Gui" were engraved onto Master Song's favorite inkstone.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>不足为外人道也。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T015558Z">
        <seg>However, he never revealed this to anyone, and Chen Ping'an was naturally oblivious to these hidden machinations as well.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>不过。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T210012Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T210012Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>不过八十余手，青衫少年就输得一塌糊涂，垂头不语，紧抿着嘴唇。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T080005Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T080005Z">
        <seg>After only fewer than 90 turns, the azure-robed young boy suffered a catastrophic loss, and he lowered his head in silence with his lips tightly pursed.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>不过刘羡阳的同龄人，可不这么说，只讲刘羡阳的祖辈，是个逃兵，是逃到了小镇这边，给人做了上门女婿，运气好才躲过官府追捕。说得板上钉钉，好似亲眼见过刘羡阳的祖辈如何逃离战场，又如何一路颠沛流离到了这座小镇。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T130635Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T130635Z">
        <seg>However, Liu Xianyang's contemporaries told a completely different story. They proclaimed that Liu Xianyang's ancestor was a deserter who had fled to the town and became a live-in son-in-law to a family here, and that he only managed to avoid being captured by authorities thanks to a huge stroke of fortune. They were extremely convinced of the authenticity of this story, as if they had personally witnessed how Liu Xianyang's ancestor had fled the battlefield before traveling to the small town. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>不过如姚老头这般钻牛角尖的人，终究少数。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T090036Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T090036Z">
        <seg>However, ultimately, people who were as pedantic as Old Man Yao were part of the minority.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>不过宋集薪对下棋兴致不大，三天打鱼两天晒网，反观资质逊色的青衫少年，既是乡塾学生，又担任书童，与齐先生朝夕相处，哪怕只是旁观先生枯坐打谱，也受益匪浅，所以青衫少年从执黑才能偶尔侥幸获胜，到如今只要执黑，胜负就能与宋集薪在五五之间，棋力手筋的进步，显而易见。对于这种此消彼长，齐先生不置一词，袖手旁观而已。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T074033Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T073731Z">
        <seg>However, Song Jixin didn't have much interest in go, and he was always slacking off in his learning of the game. In contrast, the azure-robed young boy's aptitude was inferior to his, but not only was he a student at the private school, he also served as Mr. Qi's scholarly attendant, so he was always with the teacher. Thus, he was able to learn extensively just from watching Mr. Qi play out games recorded in go manuals on his own. Hence, with the black stones, the young boy was now able to occasionally win some games. At the moment, with the black stones, he had a roughly 50:50 chance of beating Song Jixin, and his improvement over the years was very apparent. However, Mr. Qi had never commented on the dwindling skill gap between them, and he was always watching their games in silence.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>世世代代都只会烧瓷一事的小镇匠人，既不敢僭越烧制贡品官窑，也不敢将库藏瓷器私自贩卖给百姓，只得纷纷另谋出路，十四岁的陈平安也被扫地出门，回到泥瓶巷后，继续守着这栋早已破败不堪的老宅，差不多是家徒四壁的惨淡场景，便是陈平安想要当败家子，也无从下手。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T090840Z">
        <seg>For generations, the potters in the small town had only engaged in this one line of work, and they didn't dare to overstep their boundaries and continue to produce imperial ware, nor did they dare to sell their stocks of imperial ware to the common folk. Thus, they could only turn to other avenues to make ends meet. At just 14 years of age, Chen Ping'an was also kicked out, and after returning to Clay Vase Valley, he continued to reside in this old and dilapidated house under bleak and impoverished conditions. Even if he wanted to be a spendthrift rich kid, there was simply no wealth for him to squander.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>两个少年一头雾水，皆不知“座子棋”为何物。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T074327Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T074327Z">
        <seg>The two boys were both quite befuddled, with neither of them having any idea what an even game was supposed to be.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>两者之间，互视仇寇。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T084153Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T084153Z">
        <seg>Each of them was looking at one another as if they were sworn enemies.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>两鬓微霜的中年儒士转头望来，轻轻走出屋子。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T020627Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T020627Z">
        <seg>The teacher was a middle-aged scholar with gray sideburns, and he gently made his way out of the room.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>中年人的捻子、落子，动作娴熟，行云流水，让人赏心悦目。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T074511Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T074511Z">
        <seg>His motions in picking up the placing the stones were extremely fluid and well-rehearsed, presenting an elegant sight to behold.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>中年儒士俯身收拾棋子，看似东一颗西一枚，杂乱无序，实则先黑后白，从宋集薪最后落子的那枚黑子开始捡起，顺序倒推而去，一子不差。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T082613Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T082613Z">
        <seg>He then rushed away gleefully while Mr. Qi bent over to pick up the stones, seemingly in a completely haphazard fashion, but in reality, he was picking the stone up in an alternating sequence of black and white. The first stone that he picked up was the last black stone that Song Jixin had placed, and he cleared the board in the reverse order of the sequence of moves that were played, doing so with unerring accuracy.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>中年儒士点头道：“确实如此。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T074918Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T074918Z">
        <seg>"That is indeed the case," Mr. Qi replied with a nod.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>中年光棍乐了，笑嘻嘻道：“夸你长得好看呢，全是好话。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T171108Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T171108Z">
        <seg>The gatekeeper chuckled, "They were praising you for your good looks. They were all saying good things about you!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>中年读书人站起身，玉树临风，望向那位少女，冷笑道：“孽障逆种！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T083113Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T083113Z">
        <seg>Mr. Qi stood up straight like a sturdy tree in the wind, turning to the young girl with a cold sneer. "What a disgusting creature you are!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>之后少年的送信过程，也是这般平淡无奇，桃叶巷街角有户名声不显的人家，开门的是个慈眉善目的矮小老人，收起信后，笑着说了句：“小伙子，辛苦了。要不要进来歇歇，喝口热水？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T005340Z">
        <seg>The letter delivery process after this proved to be just as mundane and uneventful. On the corner of Peach Leaf Alley was a lesser known family, and Chen Ping'an was greeted by a benevolent-looking old man of a rather short and small stature. The man accepted the letter with a smile, then said, "You're working hard, young lad. Would you like to come in for some rest and a sip of warm water?"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>二月二，龙抬头。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T074231Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T074231Z">
        <seg>The second day of the second month on the lunar calendar was said to be the day that the dragon raised its head, also known as the Longtaitou Festival. [ref]The Chinese characters for Longtaitou (龙抬头) literally translate to Dragon Raising Head.[/ref]</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>人吃土一生，土吃人一回。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T203314Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T203314Z">
        <seg>Everyone relied on the earth their entire life for sustenance, but upon their death, they would be devoured by the earth in return.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>今天陈平安望向栅栏外，却发现好些人在等着开城门，不下七八人之多，男女老少，都有。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T150308Z">
        <seg>On this day, as Chen Ping'an cast his gaze out of the town gate, he was surprised to discovered that there were seven or eight people waiting outside, and there were people of both genders and all ages among them.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>他一边走向木栅栏门，一边伸手掏着裤裆。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T165502Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T165502Z">
        <seg>He made his way toward the makeshift gate while reaching a hand down into his own pants.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>他丢出一只沉甸甸的绣袋，抛给陈平安，笑脸灿烂道：“这是酬谢，你我就算两清了。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T102831Z">
        <seg>He tossed a heavy embroidered pouch to Chen Ping'an, then said with a vibrant smile, "This is my thanks to you. We're all clear now."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>他习惯性抓起一把泥土，攥在手心，缓缓揉搓。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T232135Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T232135Z">
        <seg>He habittually grabbed a handful of dirt and held it in his hand, massaging it slowly.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>他大步跨过门槛，靴子明显故意绕过了那些符纸的灰烬。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T115526Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T115526Z">
        <seg>He took a big stride over the doorstep, clearly intentionally avoiding stepping on the ashes of the burned talisman.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>他想说的是，那条奇丑无比的四脚蛇，最近额头上有隆起，如头顶生角。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T105832Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T105832Z">
        <seg>What he wanted to say was that the hideous four-legged snake had recently developed a bulge on its forehead, as if a horn were growing there.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>他曾跟随姚老头在小镇周边翻山越岭，背着沉甸甸的行囊，装有柴刀、锄头在内各色物件，满满当当。在老人的带领下，会在各处走走停停，陈平安经常需要“吃土”，抓起一把泥土就直接放入嘴中，咀嚼泥土，细细品尝滋味。久而久之，熟能生巧，陈平安哪怕只是手指研磨一番，就清楚土壤的质地。以至于在后来，市面上一些老窑口的破碎瓷片，陈平安掂量一下，就能知道是那座窑口、甚至是哪位师傅烧出来的东西。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T234136Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T234136Z">
        <seg>In the past, he had traveled extensively around the town with Old Man Yao, carrying heavy heavy bags that were filled to the brim with all types of things, such as machetes and hoes. Old Man Yao had taken him to many different places, and during their travels, Chen Ping'an was often made to "eat dirt", which included picking up a handful of dirt and placing it directly into his mouth before chewing it to carefully savor its flavor. Over time, Chen Ping'an became more proficient at the skill, and he was able to glean the properties of any soil that he came into contact with just by massaging it between his fingers. In fact, he became so skilled at this that all he had to do was weigh up some broken porcelain fragments on the market with his hand, and he would be able to tell which kiln the porcelain had come from, and even which master it had been fired by.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>他有些感慨，果然还是赚女子的钱，更容易一些。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T015359Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T015359Z">
        <seg>At the same time, he couldn't help but muse to himself that it was easier to get women to spend money on things like this.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>他没有转头，沉声道：“好自为之。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T082817Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T082817Z">
        <seg>Without turning around, Mr. Qi said in a solemn voice, "You're on your own now."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>他瞥见少年手中的泥土，略作停顿，促狭道：“就是面朝黄土背朝天的命了。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T071126Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T071126Z">
        <seg>He paused momentarily as he spotted the dirt in Chen Ping'an's hand, then continued in a menacing fashion, "Then you're going to be buried in the dirt before long."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>他突然说道：“你去赵繇那边看看，就当提前道别。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T082344Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T082344Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>他让陈平安等着，大踏步走向屋子，回来的时候，手里多了一摞信封，不厚不薄，约莫十来份，汉子递给陈平安后，问道：“傻人有傻福，好人有好报。你信不信？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T172305Z">
        <seg>The gatekeeper asked Chen Ping'an to wait outside as he made his way into the cabin, then re-emerged with a stack of letters in his hand. It wasn't a particularly thick stack, consisting of only around 10 letters, and the man handed the letters over to Chen Ping'an before asking, "It's said that fortune favors the foolish, and karma favors the righteous. Do you believe in that?"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>他转头对自家丫鬟笑道：“稚圭，咱们走！去给你买一整个将军肚子罐的桃花粉。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T202711Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T202711Z">
        <seg>He then put on a smile as he turned to Zhi Gui and said, "Let's Go, Zhi Gui. I'll buy you a whole temple jar of peach blossom powder."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>传闻小镇曾经有好事者，试图检验铁链到底有多长，不顾老人们的劝阻，对于“拽铁锁出井口者，每出一尺，折寿一年”，这条口口相传的老规矩，那人根本没当回事，结果使劲拉扯了一炷香后，拔出一大堆铁链，仍是没有看到尽头的迹象，那人已是精疲力尽，便任由那些拽出井口的铁链，盘曲在水井轱辘旁，说是明天再来，他就偏偏不信这个邪了。此人回到家后，当天便七窍流血，暴毙在床上，而且死不瞑目，不管家人如何费劲折腾，尸体就是闭不上眼睛，最后有一个世世代代住在水井附近的老人，让那户人家抬着尸体到水井旁边，“眼睁睁”看着老人将那些铁链放回水井，等到整条铁链重新笔直没入井口深水中，那具尸体终于闭眼了。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T092025Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T092025Z">
        <seg>It was said that there was once a curious individual in the town who wanted to examine just how long the chain was. The old people in the town warned them that those who tried to pull the chain out of the well would have one year shaved off their lifespan with each foot of chain that was pulled, but the man paid no heed to the ominous warning. After tugging vigorously on the chain for 15 minutes, a huge pile of it had been pulled out, but there was still no end in sight. At that point, the man was already completely exhausted, and he left the pile of chain next to the well winch, proclaiming that he was going to be back the next day, and that he was determined to get to the bottom of this mystery. However, on the very same day after he returned home, he died on his bed, bleeding out of all of his orifices, and he refused to close his eyes in death. No matter what his family members tried, they were unable to get his corpse to close its eyes. In the end, an old man whose family had lived near the well for generations instructed that family to carry the corpse over to the well so that it could "watch" the old man return the chain back into the well. Finally, after the entire chain had sunk down into the depths, the body finally closed its eyes.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>但是在那之后，刘羡阳非但没有感激那个救了自己命的孩子，反而隔三差五就来这边捉弄戏耍，孤儿也倔，不管刘羡阳如何欺负，就是不肯哭，让少年愈发愤懑。只是后来有一年，刘羡阳眼见着那个姓陈的小孤儿，估计是实在扛不过冬天的样子，终于良心发现，已经在龙窑拜师学艺的少年，便带着孤儿去往那座位于宝溪边上的龙窑，出了小镇往西走，大雪天的几十里山路，刘羡阳到现在还是没有想明白，那个长得跟木炭似的小家伙，两条腿分明细得跟毛竹竿子差不多，是怎么走到龙窑的？不过老姚头虽然最后还是留下了陈平安，但对待两人，确实天壤之别，对关门弟子刘羡阳，也打也骂，但瞎子也感受得到其中的良苦用心，例如有次下手重了，砸得刘羡阳额头渗出血来，少年皮糙肉厚没觉得有什么，反而是当师傅的老姚头，很是后悔了，这个在徒弟面前威严惯了的闷葫芦老头，碍于面子不好说什么，结果在自家屋子里兜圈子兜了大半夜，仍是不放心刘羡阳，最后只得喊来陈平安，给刘羡阳送去了一瓶药膏。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T043906Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T043906Z">
        <seg>However, after that incident, not only was Liu Xianyang not grateful to the child that saved his life, he regularly came over to bully the child instead. The child was an orphan, and he was very stubborn, refusing to cry no matter how much he was bullied, something that only served to further infuriate Liu Xianyang. One year, Liu Xianyang could tell that the little orphan most likely wasn't going to be able to make it through the winter, and he was finally stung by his conscience. Having already become a disciple of Old Man Yao's at the time, he took the young boy to the dragon kiln that was situated beside Treasure Creek. They headed west out of the town, traveling over dozens of kilometers of rugged mountain terrain under heavy snowfall. To this day, Liu Xianyang still couldn't understand how the emaciated young boy with a pair of legs as thin as baby bamboo shoots had managed to walk all the way to the dragon kiln. Even though Old Man Yao ultimately took in Chen Ping'an, the disparity in his treatment of the two boys was night and day. Even as his best disciple, Liu Xianyang wasn't spared from his beatings and insults, but even a blind man could sense the good intentions behind Old Man Yao's words and actions. For example, there was one time when he went a little too far, inflicting a bleeding gash onto Liu Xianyang's forehead. As a tough young boy, Liu Xianyang didn't think much of this, but Old Man Yao was feeling very remorseful over his actions. However, he had always kept up a stern and authoritative facade in front of his disciples, so he couldn't bring himself to apologize or enquire about his condition. In the end, he paced back and forht in his own room for almost an entire night, and he was still concerned about Liu Xianyang. Finally, he had no choice but to call over Chen Ping'an to deliver a bottle of ointment to Liu Xianyang.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>但是外乡人能不能进入小镇，男人却掌握着生杀大权。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T165426Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T165426Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>偏偏树叶在空中又打了一个旋儿。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230751Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T230751Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>偏居一隅的小镇，没有什么所谓的书香门第，所以读书人，堪称凤毛麟角。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T073104Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T073104Z">
        <seg>There were no highly educated families in this secluded little town, so scholars were exceedingly rare here.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>关于这位独来独往的桀骜少年，小镇流传诸多说法，但是少年喜欢自称祖上是带兵打仗的将军，所以他家才会有那件一代代传承下来的宝甲。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T123627Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T123627Z">
        <seg>There were many stories about the unruly young man going around in the town. However, the story that he personally liked to perptuate was that his ancestor was a general who led armies in battle, which was why there was a prized suit of armor that had been passed down for generations in his family.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>其实，年轻道人袖中所藏两支竹签，一支是最上签，一支是最下签，都是用来挣大钱的。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T015535Z">
        <seg>As it turned out, there were two bamboo slips concealed up the taoist priest's sleeve, one of which was the best possible slip, while the other was the worst possible slip, and both of them were reserved for earning big money.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>再往前，陈平安路过一座石牌坊，由于牌坊楼修建有十二根石柱，当地人喜欢把它称为螃蟹牌坊，这座牌坊的真实名字，宋集薪和刘阳羡的说法很不一样，宋集薪信誓旦旦说在一本叫地方县志的老书上，称这里为大学士坊，是皇帝老爷的御赐牌坊，为了纪念历史上一位大官的治武功。与陈平安一般土包子的刘阳羡，则说这就是螃蟹坊，咱们都喊了几百年了，没理由叫什么狗屁不通的大学士坊。刘阳羡还问宋集薪一个问题，“大学士的官帽子到底有多大，是不是比铁锁井的井口还大”，问得宋集薪满脸涨红。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T141610Z">
        <seg>Jogging ahead a bit further, Chen Ping'an passed by a stone archway. Due to the fact that the archway was supported by 12 stone pillars, the local residents liked to refer to it as the crab archway. As for what the archway's actual name was, Song Jixin and Liu Yangxian had very different accounts. Song Jixin swore that he had read on an old book by the name of "Local County Chronicles" that the archway was called the Grand Secretary Archway, and that it had been bestowed upon the town by the emperor at the time to commemorate a official in history who had made significant contributions in overseeing military forces. In contrast, Liu Xianyang was just as much of a hillbilly as Chen Ping'an, and he insisted that this place was known as the Crab Archway. It had been referred to as such for several centuries, and in his eyes, there was no reason to give it a nonsensical name like the Grand Secretary Arch. In addition to that, Liu Xianyang had also posed a question to Song Jixin: "How big is the official hat of a grand secretary? Is it bigger than the opening of the Iron Lock Well?"

Song Jixin had no answer to this, and he was left flushing furiously with embarrassment.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>再绕过一条街，陈平安就听到不远处传来一阵熟悉的读书声，那里有座乡塾，是小镇几个大户人家合伙凑钱开的，教书先生是外乡人，陈平安小的时候，经常跑去躲在窗外，偷偷蹲着，竖起耳朵。那位先生虽然教书的时候极为严苛，但是对陈平安这些“蹭读书蹭蒙学”的孩子，也不呵斥拦阻，后来陈平安去了小镇外的一座龙窑做学徒，就再没有去过学塾。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T141548Z">
        <seg>After passing through another street, Chen Ping'an heard the familiar sound of reading ringing out nearby. There was a private school there, and it was jointly funded by several of the most affluent families in the town. The teacher was from out of town, and back in his younger days, Chen Ping'an would often squat down outside the window and listen to the lesson being taught in secret. The teaching was very strict during classes, but he never called out or got in the way of freeloaders like Chen Ping'an. After that, Chen Ping'an traveled out of the town to become a disciple at a dragon kiln, and he hadn't visited the school since then.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>凌寒花了整整十秒钟的时间，才终于肯定，他确实转世重生了。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Yuanl" changedate="20230318T054851Z" creationid="Yuanl" creationdate="20230318T054851Z">
        <seg>ppkease commit</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>刘羡阳伸手指了指在远处停步的道人，“以后见你一次打一次！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T204543Z">
        <seg>Liu Xianyang pointed at the taoist priest, who had stopped in the distance, and threatened, "From now on, I'm gonna beat you up everytime I see you!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>刘羡阳似乎觉得犹不过瘾，做了个稀奇古怪的踢腿动作，笑道：“这叫好腿必入裆，踢死闷倒驴！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T120619Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T120619Z">
        <seg>He didn't seem to be satisfied with his performance, and he subsquently made a strange kicking motion as he continued, "As the saying goes, a good kick to the crotch can kill a drunk donkey!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>刘羡阳冷不丁转身，快步如飞跑向算命摊子，一边摩拳擦掌，一边嚷着：“烧香是吧，我先烧了你的摊子！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T204328Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T204328Z">
        <seg>Liu Xianyang suddenly turned around before rushing toward the fortune telling stall like the wind, putting on a menacing display as he scoffed, "You want me to burn incense? How about I burn down your stall first!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>刘羡阳大踏步离开泥瓶巷。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T123359Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T123359Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>刘羡阳得意洋洋道：“我家阮师傅出了小镇后，在南边那条溪边上，突然就说要挖几口井，原先人手不够，需要喊人帮忙，我就随口提了提你，说有个矮冬瓜，气力还凑合。阮师傅也答应了，让你这两天就自己过去。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T114301Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T114108Z">
        <seg>A smug look appeared on Liu Xianyang's face as he continued, "While Master Ruan was out of town and passing by the creek to the south, he suddenly told me that he wanted to dig a few wells. He doesn't have enough people for the job and wants some more help, so I mentioned you to him on a whim. I told him that I know a short kid who has some decent strength, and Master Ruan agreed. He wants you to go and see him in the next couple of days.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>刘羡阳恼羞成怒道：“你知道什么好什么坏？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T113139Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T113139Z">
        <seg>Liu Xianyang was furious to hear this. "How would you know? You don't even know the diffference between good and bad!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>刘羡阳抬起一只手掌，“打住打住！大恩不言谢！记在心里就好！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T114149Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T114149Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>刘羡阳挠挠头，站起身，也没说什么愧疚言语，只是轻轻踹了一脚陈平安，咧嘴笑道：“行了，不就一张小破床嘛，我今天来，就是给你带一个天大的好消息，怎么都比你这破床值钱！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T113625Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T113625Z">
        <seg>Liu Xianyang scratched his head as he stood up, and he didn't apologize or express any guilt. Instead, he gave Chen Ping'an a playful kick as he grinned and said, "Get over it, it's just a crappy little bed. I'm here today to deliver a massive piece of good news to you, one that's way more valuable than this crappy bed!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>刘羡阳有些惊讶，记得这道士以前给人解签算命，且不说准不准，但此人还真没有主动招徕过生意，几乎全部属于愿者上钩。难不成如今龙窑给朝廷官府关闭，这道士也要跟着倒霉，揭不开锅了，所以宁肯错杀不愿错放？刘羡阳笑骂道：“你的法门就是破财消灾，对不对？滚你大爷的，想从我兜里骗钱，下辈子吧！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T203941Z">
        <seg>Liu Xianyang was rather surprised to hear this. He knew that this taoist priest had always been telling people's fortunes based on the slips that they drew, and setting aside whether his fortune-telling was accurate or not, Liu Xianyang couldn't ever recall an instance where the taoist priest had actively tried to rope in customers. Almost all of his customers had voluntarily gone to him. Could it be that with the closing of the dragon kilns, the taoist priest's business was also impacted, and he was struggling to get by, thereby leading him to go after all potential customers with discretion? 

Liu Xianyang chuckled in disdain, "The way you're going to help me avert disaster is by having me give you money, right? Piss off! You're never getting a single copper coin out of my pocket!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>刘羡阳此时才发现陈平安在做一件古怪的勾当，蹲在门内，身体向外倾，用一截只剩下拇指大小的蜡烛，烧掉一张黄纸，灰烬都落在门槛外。貌似陈平安还念念有词，只是离得有些远，刘羡阳听得不真切。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T031210Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T031027Z">
        <seg>Only now did he notice that Chen Ping'an was doing something rather strange. He was squatted down inside the doorstep with his body leaning forward, using a candle to burn a piece of yellow paper. Only around a thumb's length of the candle remained, and all of the ashes of burned piece of paper fell outside of the doorstep. It seemed that Chen Ping'an was also chanting something, but Liu Xianyang was too far away to hear what he was saying.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>刘羡阳犹豫片刻，破天荒微微脸红，“就像春天猫叫一样。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T112032Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T112032Z">
        <seg>Liu Xianyang hesitated momentarily, and in an extremely rare and uncharacteristic display of embarrassment, he blushed slightly as he continued, "Like how cats sound during spring?"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>刘羡阳环顾四周，墙角斜放着一根鱼竿，窗口躺着一副弹弓，墙壁上挂着木弓，高大少年欲言又止，最后还是忍住没开口。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T115447Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T115447Z">
        <seg>Liu Xianyang looked around and noticed a fishing rod placed on a slant in the corner, a slingshot on the windowsill, and a wooden bow hanging on the wall. He was about to say something, but refrained from doing so in the end.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>刘羡阳看着陈平安将蜡烛吹灭，放在桌上，低声问道：“你平时清晨有没有听到过古怪的声响，就像”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T111931Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T111931Z">
        <seg>Liu Xianyang watched as Chen Ping'an blew out the candle before setting it down on the table, then asked, "Have you heard any strange sounds in the morning? Like..."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>刘羡阳眼神呆滞。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T113344Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T113344Z">
        <seg>Liu Xianyang was quite taken aback to hear this.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>刘羡阳眼角余光瞥见那隔壁丫鬟已经进了屋子，便一下子没了扮演英雄好汉的兴致，</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T122902Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T122902Z">
        <seg>Out of the corner of his eye, Liu Xianyang could see that Zhi Gui had already entered the neigboring house, and he immediately lost all interest in keeping up his heroic act.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>刘羡阳离开小巷，经过算命摊子的时候，那年轻道人招收道：“来来来，贫道看你气色如烈火烹油，绝非吉兆啊，不过莫怕便是，贫道有一法，可以帮你消灾”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T203557Z">
        <seg>After leaving the alley, Liu Xianyang was just passing by the fortune teller's stall when the young taoist priest called out to him. "Come, young man! I can see that you have the complexion of a fire fueled by oil. That's definitely not a good omen! But do not fear, I have a way to help you avert disaster!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>刘羡阳突然转过身，面对门槛内的陈平安，高大少年一坐腰，脚不离地，直冲数步后，重重挥出一拳，然后收拳挺腰，大声笑道：“阮师傅私底下跟我说，这拳法我只需要练一年，就能打死人！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T115842Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T115842Z">
        <seg>He then crouched down into a low stance before shuffling a few steps toward Chen Ping'an, then threw a heavy punch in his direction. After that, he stood up straight again as he withdrew his fist and chortled, "Master Ruan told me in private that I'll only need to practice this fist technique for a year, and I'll be able to kill someone with a single punch!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>刘羡阳站在摊子旁边，看着道人的狼狈身影，哈哈大笑，瞥见桌上的签筒，随意伸手将其推倒，竹签哗啦啦滑出签筒，最后在桌上呈现出扇形模样。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T204506Z">
        <seg>Liu Xianyang stood beside the stall, chortling with mirth at the sight of the taoist priest's cowardly display. He then spotted the bamboo tube on the table and casually pushed it over. All of the bamboo slips inside were instantly tipped out, fanning themselves out across the table.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>刘羡阳翻了个白眼，不再对牛弹琴，双手撑在床板上，缓缓弯曲手肘，然后伸直手臂，屁股离开床板，双脚离开地面。他的屁股悬在空中，撇嘴讥讽道：“什么稚圭，分明是叫王朱，姓宋的从小就喜欢瞎显摆，不知道从哪里看到稚圭两个字，就胡乱用了，根本不管两个字的意思好不好。王朱摊上这么个公子，也真是上辈子作孽，否则不至于来宋集薪身边遭罪吃苦。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T112714Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T112714Z">
        <seg>Liu Xianyang rolled his eyes and didn't waste any more time discussing the subject with someone who was clearly completely oblivious to what he was talking about. He placed his palms down onto the bed plank, then bent his elbows slightly before straightening his arms, supporting his own weight with his hands so that his bottom lifted up from the plank and his feet were lifted up from the ground. He then pursed his lips as he sneered, "What kind of name is Zhi Gui supposed to be? Her name is clearly Wang Zhu. That little Song brat always liked to show off ever since he was a wee little pipsqueak. He probably just saw the characters Zhi Gui from somewhere and decided to use it on a whim without even considering whether that name has good implications or not. Wang Zhu had to have accumulated a ton of bad karma in her past life. Otherwise, she wouldn't have been reincarnated as Song Jixin's servant and been forced to lead such a miserable life."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>刘羡阳这才罢休。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T204632Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T204622Z">
        <seg>Liu Xianyang was finally willing to let him off the hook.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>刘羡阳，正是一座老字号龙窑姚老头的关门弟子，至于资质鲁钝的陈平安，老人从头到尾根本就没真正认下这个徒弟，在当地，徒弟没有敬拜师茶，或是师父没有喝过那杯茶，就等于没有师徒名分。陈平安和刘羡阳不是邻居，双方祖宅离着挺远，之所以刘羡阳当时会跟姚老头介绍陈平安，源于当个少年有过一段陈年恩怨，刘羡阳曾是小镇出了名顽劣少年，爷爷去世前，家里好歹还有个长辈管着，等到他爷爷病逝后，十二三岁就身高马大不输青壮男子的少年，成了街坊邻居人人头疼的混世魔王，后来不知为何，刘羡阳惹恼了一伙卢家子弟，结果给人死死堵在泥瓶巷里，结结实实的一顿痛打，对方都是正值气盛的少年，下手从不计较轻重，刘羡阳很快给打得呕血不止，住在泥瓶巷的十多户人家，多是小龙窑讨碗饭吃的底层匠户，哪敢掺和这浑水。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T032935Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T032626Z">
        <seg>Liu Xianyang was Old Man Yao's best disciple. As for Chen Ping'an, Old Man Yao had never truly accepted him as a disciple due to his mediocre aptitude for the craft. According to local traditions, no master and disciple relationship could be established unless the disciple offered a cup of tea to the master in a formal ceremony, and the master accepted and drank the cup of tea. Chen Ping'an and Liu Xianyang weren't neighbors. In fact, their ancestral homes were quite far away from one another's. The reason why Liu Xianyang had recommended Chen Ping'an to Old Man Yao stemmed from their past history. Liu Xianyang was once a renowned delinquent in the town. Prior to the passing of his grandfather, there was at least an adult in the household to keep him in check, but after his grandfather passed away due to illness, Liu Xianyang quickly became an absolute nightmare for his neighbors. At the time, he was only 12 or 13 years old, but he was already no less physically developed than a young man, and one time, he somehow made enemies out of a group of boys from the Lu Family. As a result, he was ganged up on in Clay Vase Alley and handed a vicious beating. His assailants were all young boys who didn't think about the consequences of their actions, and Liu Xianyang was quickly beaten to hte point where he was throwing up blood. All of the dozen or so families that resided in Clay Vase Alley were bottom-class potters who made a living by working at small dragon kilns, and they didn't dare to intervene.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>到最后，只有一个枯瘦如柴的孩子，偷偷溜出院子后，跑到了巷口，对着大街撕心裂肺喊道：“死人啦死人啦”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T033251Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T033251Z">
        <seg>In the end, the only one who did anything was an emaciated child, who snuck out of his yard and rushed to the entrance of the alley, where he screamed with all his might, "Help! Someone's about to die here!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>前一世的他，站在了武道巅峰，更在丹道上有着前无古人的成就，开创的“三火引”之术在炼丹界引发了一场革命，被尊称为“丹帝”。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Yuanl" changedate="20230318T055111Z" creationid="Yuanl" creationdate="20230318T055111Z">
        <seg>dsad</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>卢、李、赵、宋四个姓氏，在小镇这边是大姓，乡塾就是这几家出的钱，在城外大多拥有两三座大龙窑。历任窑务督造官的官邸，就和这几户人家在一条街上。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T173853Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T173853Z">
        <seg>Lu, Li, Zhao, Song were the most prominent surnames in the town, and it was those families who had pooled together the funds to open the private school. Each of those families owned two or three large dragon kilns outside the town, and all of the past kiln supervision officials had lived on the same street as them.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>双方性情，天壤之别。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T075908Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T075908Z">
        <seg>The difference in their personalities was night and day.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>双鬓霜白的儒雅文士点头道：“一旬之内，就会离开。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T080656Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T080656Z">
        <seg>The scholar nodded in response. "I will be leaving within 10 days."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>只是一阵清风拂过，树叶从他手边滑过。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230713Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T230713Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>只是被人有意无意看了一眼，陈平安纯粹下意识地后退了一步。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T170342Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T170342Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>只见那位先生始终站在门口，身影沐浴在阳光中，远远望去，恍若神人。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021026Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T021026Z">
        <seg>The teacher was still standing at the entrance, basking under the sunlight, resembling a deity from afar.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>可他并不满足，还想要再进一步，达到传说中的破虚境，破碎虚空、化凡成神。为此，他探访了无数的古迹，最终进入了黑血谷，历经重重危险之后找到了一座神秘的古塔。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Yuanl" changedate="20230318T055115Z" creationid="Yuanl" creationdate="20230318T055115Z">
        <seg>However,</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>可是少年从未埋怨过老人，更不会记恨。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T065400Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T065400Z">
        <seg>However, Chen Ping'an had never resented or hated Old Man Yao.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>各自返回屋子，陈平安关上门，躺在坚硬的木板床上，贫寒少年闭上眼睛，小声呢喃道：“碎碎平，岁岁安，碎碎平安，岁岁平安”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T110536Z">
        <seg>The two young boys returned to their respective homes, and Chen Ping'an closed the door as he laid down on his plank bed, then closed his eyes as he quietly murmured to himself, "May there be peace all year round, may there be safety all year round, may I be safe and peaceful all year round."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>听到“死人”二字，卢家子弟这才悚然惊醒，看到地上满身血污的刘羡阳，高大少年奄奄一息，那些个富家少年郎总算感到一阵后怕，面面相觑后，便从泥瓶巷另一端跑掉。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T033436Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T033436Z">
        <seg>Only after hearing the word "die" did the boys from the Lu Family receive a rude awakening. At that point, Liu Xianyang's entire body was covered in blood, and he was on the brink of death. The boys from the Lu Family finally felt a sense of fear at what they had done upon seeing this, and after exchanging a few glances with one another, they quickly fled down the other end of Clay Vase Alley.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>在泥瓶巷长大的少女，此时满脸懵懂神色，柔柔弱弱怯怯，楚楚可怜。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T082854Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T082854Z">
        <seg>At this moment, Zhi Gui wore a dazed and timid look on her face, striking the beholder with a sense of sympathy.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>在陈平安的记忆中，好像这位云游至此的年轻道爷，在小镇已经待了最少五六年，模样倒是没什么变化，对谁也都和和气气的，平时就是帮人摸骨看相、算卦抽签，偶尔也能代写家书，有意思的是，桌案上那只拥簇着一百零八支竹签的签筒，这么多年来，小镇男男女女抽签，既没有谁抽出过上上签，也没有谁从签筒摇晃出一支下签，仿佛整整一百零八签，签签中上无坏签。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T012500Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an recalled that this young traveling taoist priest had already been staying in this town for at least the past five or six years. His appearance hadn't changed much during that time, and he was always quite friendly to everyone. On a normal day, all he did was tell people's fortunes through scapulimancy, face reading, and slip drawing, and he also occasionally acted as a letter ghost writer for others. What was rather interesting was that there were 108 bamboo slips in the slip tube on the table, but during all his time here, not a single person had managed to draw the best possible slip, nor had anyone ever drawn a slip of misfortune. It was as if there were only good or neutral slips in the tube with no other options available.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>塾师齐先生今天不知为何，破天荒早早结束了授业。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T071828Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T071828Z">
        <seg>For some reason, Mr. Qi from the private school concluded the lessons early on this day, something that he almost never did.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>大概每过一刻钟，少年就会歇息稍许时分，抖抖手腕，如此循环反复，直到整个人彻底精疲力尽，陈平安这才起身，一边在院中散步，一边缓缓舒展筋骨。从来没有人教过陈平安这些，是他自己瞎琢磨出来的门道。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T094221Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T094221Z">
        <seg>Once ever 15 minutes, he would take a short break to shake out his wrists. Only after repeating this process until he was completely exhausted did he rise to his feet, strolling through the yard while performing some stretches. No one had taught him to do any of this, it was just a routine that he had made up himself.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>天地间原本万籁寂静，陈平安听到一声刺耳的讥讽笑声，停下脚步，果不其然，看到那个同龄人蹲在墙头上，咧着嘴，毫不掩饰他的鄙夷神色。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T094918Z">
        <seg>All of a sudden, the peace and quiet was punctuated by the harsh sound of a mocking jeer. Chen Ping'an stopped in his tracks, and just as he expected, there was a boy roughly the same age as him squatting on the top of the wall, looking down at him with a derisive sneer, making no effort to hide his disdain.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>天微微亮，尚未鸡鸣，陈平安就已经起床，单薄的被褥，实在留不住热气，而且陈平安在烧瓷学徒的时候，也养成了早起晚睡的习惯。陈平安打开屋门，来到泥土松软的小院子，深呼吸一口气后，伸了个懒腰，走出院子，转头看到一个纤弱身影，弯着腰，双手拎着一木桶水，正用肩膀顶开自家院门，正是宋集薪的婢女，她应该是刚从杏花巷那边的铁锁井打水回来。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T113137Z">
        <seg>Dawn was only just breaking, and Chen Ping'an had already gotten up even before the roosters were crowing. His thin blanket didn't do a very good job of keeping him warm, and he had developed the habit of waking up early and going to bed late back when he was learning to become a potter. He opened the door before stepping out onto the soft and loamy soil in the courtyard outside, then took a deep breath. After stretching out his body, he made his way out of the courtyard and turned to discover a thin and frail figure. It was none other than Song Jixin's maidservant, and she huddled over, trying to open the gate of the neighboring courtyard with her shoulder while carrying a bucket of water with both hands. It seemed that she had just drawn some water from the Iron Lock Well in Apricot Blossom Valley.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>天真无邪。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T082941Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T082941Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>头戴莲花冠的年轻道人，收拾着摊子，唉声叹息，相熟的小镇百姓问起缘由，也只是摇头晃脑不作答。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T090633Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T090633Z">
        <seg>The young daoist priest in the lotus hat was packing up his stall while sighing in dismay. The town residents who were familiar with him asked him why he was so glum, but he merely shook his head and refused to answer.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>头顶突然飘落一片槐叶，苍翠欲滴，刚好落在少年额头上。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230534Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T230534Z">
        <seg>All of a sudden, a vibrant, green locust leaf came fluttering down from above, and it just so happened to land on his forehead.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>她不知道如何安慰自家公子。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T221451Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T221451Z">
        <seg>Zhi Gui didn't know how to console him.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>她好像在说，你能奈我何？</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T084107Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T084107Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>她就这样与儒士直直对视。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T084136Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T084136Z">
        <seg>The two of them stared directly at one another, and it was as if a confrontation between a dragon and a serpent were taking place.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>她推开柴门，小跑着与教书先生擦身而过，跑出几步后，她不忘转身，对那个背影施了个万福，嗓音婉约可人，“先生，稚圭先走了。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T090428Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T090428Z">
        <seg>She pushed the wooden door open, then jogged past Mr. Qi. After running a few steps, she turned around and extended a curtsy toward him as she said in a gentle and adorable voice, "I'll be leaving now, Sir."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>她没有说话。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T224833Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T224833Z">
        <seg>Zhi Gui didn't say anything.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>她羞赧道：“小小的蛐蛐罐就够了。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T202819Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T202819Z">
        <seg>"Just a small cricket jar's worth is enough," Zhi Gui said with a shy expression.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>如今自己这位婢女，有着一张刚开始褪去婴儿肥的侧脸，她好像跟记忆里那个瘦瘦小小、干干瘪瘪的小丫鬟，有了很大的出入。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T213310Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T213310Z">
        <seg>Zhi Gui had a side facial profile that was only just beginning to graduate from its baby fat stage. She was far different from the thin and emaciated little maidservant in Song Jixin's memories.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>如果没有去过福鹿街或是桃叶巷，陈平安可能这辈子，都不会意识到泥瓶巷的阴暗狭窄。不过草鞋少年非但没有生出失落的感觉，反而终于感到心安，少年笑着伸出双手，刚好掌心触碰到两遍的黄泥墙壁，记得大概三四年前，陈平安还只能双手指尖触及泥墙。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T024133Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T022025Z">
        <seg>If he hadn't gone to Fortune Deer Street and Peach Leaf Alley, perhaps Chen Ping'an would've never realized just how dark and confined Clay Vase Valley was. However, not only was he not disheartened by his own living condition, he felt a sense of reassurance. He smiled as he extended both hands outward, and his wingspan was just enough so that he was able to touch the earthen walls on either side of him. He recalled that around three to four years ago, he was only able to touch those walls with the tips of his fingers.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>如鼠见猫。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T170343Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T170343Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>妇人男孩身后的小女孩，被一位满头霜雪的魁梧老人牵着，她转头对着陈平安说了一大串话，不忘对身前同龄人男孩指指点点。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T170207Z">
        <seg>As for the little girl behind the boy and the woman, she was being led by a physically imposing elderly man with a head of white hair. She turned to Chen Ping'an and immediately began chatting away while pointing at the boy up ahead.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>婢女低声好奇问道：“三尺气概是什么？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T212209Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T212114Z">
        <seg>"What's a three-foot mettle?" Zhi Gui asked with a curious expression.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>婢女又问道：“洞天福地又是什么？世上真有人能够活三百岁吗？还有那酆都地府，不是死人才能去的地方吗？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T212510Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T212510Z">
        <seg>Zhi Gui then asked, "What is a blessed paradise? Does there really exist someone in this world that can live for 300 years? Also, isn't the underworld a place that only dead people go to?"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>婢女并未答话，低敛眼眉，依稀可见睫毛微微颤动。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T220905Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T220905Z">
        <seg>Zhi Gui offered no response as she lowered her head, and it could be seen that her eyelashes were trembling slight.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>婢女抬头望向老槐树，细细碎碎的光线透过树叶缝隙，洒落下来，她下意识眯起眼眸。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T213149Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T213149Z">
        <seg>Zhi Gui raised her head to look up at the old locust tree, and she reflexively narrowed her eyes against the fragmented rays of light filtering through the gaps in the tree's canopy.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>婢女没好气道：“公子，这位老人家，也忒喜欢卖弄学问了，话也不好好说。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T212342Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T212342Z">
        <seg>"This old man is way too pretentious and full of himself! He can't even speak properly!" Zhi Gui grumbled.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>婢女眨了眨那双秋水长眸，“难道不是字面意思？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T225631Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T225202Z">
        <seg>Zhi Gui blinked innocently as she replied, "Doesn't it just mean what it says?" </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>婢女稚圭每逢自家少爷与人下棋，都会去竹林散步，以免打扰到三位“读书人”，今天也不例外。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T073033Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T073033Z">
        <seg>Whenever her young master played go with Mr. Qi, Zhi Gui would always go to take a stroll in the bamboo forest so that she didn't disturb them, and this day was no exception.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>婢女认真想了想，回答道：“有些事，也讲缘分的吧？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T224732Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T224732Z">
        <seg>Zhi Gui considered the question carefully before replying, "Perhaps some things are simply down to fate."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>婢女轻声道：“公子，不至于吧？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T225159Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T225159Z">
        <seg>"Surely not, Young Master," Zhi Gui replied.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>学塾后头有个院子，北面开了一个矮矮的小柴门，能够通往竹林。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T072003Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T072003Z">
        <seg>Behind the private school was a yard, to the north of which was a small door constructed from firewood, and it opened up to the bamboo forest outside.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪一屁股坐在青衫少年对面，坐北朝南。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T072943Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T072943Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin sat down across from the azure-robed young boy, facing the south, while Mr. Qi was seated over in the west, watching the go board in silence.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪不知何时站在院墙那边，身边跟着婢女稚圭，他喊道：“要不要跟咱们一起去槐树那边耍？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T202405Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T202405Z">
        <seg>Before he knew it, Song Jixin had appeared on the other side of the wall with Zhi Gui in accompaniment, and he yelled, "Wanna come play with us at the locust tree?"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪伸出大拇指，开怀道：“正是这个道理！他陈平安就是个缘浅福薄之人，能活着就知足吧。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T224825Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T224825Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin gave her a thumbs-up as he happily agreed, "That's exactly right! Chen Ping'an is just someone who isn't blessed with any fortune. He should be satifised with just being alive."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪伸手抓住树叶，双指拧转叶柄。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230549Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T230549Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin grabbed the leaf and twirled its stem in between two of his fingers.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪刚要去抓棋子，齐先生突然说道：“今日你们下一盘座子棋，执白先行。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T074305Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T074050Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin was just about to grab some stones when Mr. Qi suddenly said, "Play an even game today. White goes first."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪半真半假道：“有些物件我肯定搬不走，你可别趁我家没人，就肆无忌惮地偷东西。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T110015Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T110015Z">
        <seg>"There are some things that I definitely won't be able to take with me, you'd better not steal anything while I'm gone!" Song Jixin said, half in jest.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪双手负后，昂首挺胸，大步前行，“我宋家人，钟鸣鼎食，世代簪缨，如何能够小家子气，岂非有辱家风？！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T202947Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T202947Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin clasped his hands behind his back, taking large strides forward with his head raised and his chest puffed out as he said, "Our Song Family has been living in luxury and affluence for generations! I would be bringing shame to my family if I were to be so stingy!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪和他的婢女，在这座小镇上，一直是福禄街和桃叶巷的富人们，在茶余饭后的重要谈资，这要归功于宋集薪的那个“便宜老爹”，宋大人。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T221656Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T221656Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin and Zhi Gui had always been a popular subject for gossip for the affluent families on Fortune Deer Street and Peach Leaf Alley, and that was primarily thanks to Master Song, Song Jixin's illegitimate father.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪和她并肩站在树荫边缘，看到一个老人站在树底下，一手托大白碗，一手负身后，神色激昂，正大声说道：“方才说过了大致的龙脉走向，我再来说说这真龙，啧啧，这可就真了不得了，约莫三千年前，天底下出了一位了不得的神仙人物，先是在某座洞天福地潜心修行，证了大道，便独自仗剑游历天下，手中三尺气概，锋芒毕露。不知为何，此人偏偏与蛟龙不对付，整整三百个春秋，有蛟龙处斩蛟龙，杀得世间再无真龙，这才罢休，最后不知所踪，有人说他是去了极高的道法张本之地，与道祖坐而论道，也有说是去了极远的西方净土佛国，与佛陀辩经说法，更有人说他亲自坐镇酆都地府的大门，防止魑魅魍魉为祸人间……”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T211657Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin and Zhi Gui stood side by side at the edge of the tree's shadow, and he spotted an old man standing at the foot of the tree. The man was holding a large white bowl in one hand with his other hands clasped behind his back, and he wore a vehement expression as he loudly declared, "Just now, I spoke about the general direction of the dragon vein. Now, let me tell you about the true dragon. This is a truly amazing story. Around 3,000 years ago, an almighty deity appeared under the heavens. First, he cultivated patiently in a certain blessed paradise, and after attaining the great tao, he explored the world on his own with his sword by his side. With his three-foot mettle in his hand, his prowess was unmatched. For some reason, he had a vendetta against dragons, and he spent three entire centuries hunting for dragons, only stopping after there was no longer a single true dragon in the world. In the end, he disappeared with a trace. Some speculated that he had gone to an extremely high plane where the great tao originated to discuss taoism with the patriarch of taoism himself. Some said that he had gone to the extremely distant western pure land of Sukhavati to discuss scriptures and Buddhism with the Buddha. There are even some who say that he's personally stationed at the gates of the underworld to prevent malicious wraiths and spirits from wreaking havoc upon the human plane..."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪和婢女在老槐树下听故事的时候，被人喊来下棋，宋集薪不太情愿，只是那人说是齐先生的意思，想要看一看他们棋力有无长进，宋集薪对于不苟言笑的齐先生，有一种说不清道不明的观感，大概可以称之为既敬且畏，所以齐先生亲自下了这道圣旨，宋集薪不得不赴约，但是他一定要等说书先生讲完故事，再去学塾后院。帮先生传话的青衫少年，只得先行打道回府，不忘叮嘱宋集薪千万别太晚到，絮絮叨叨，还是老调重弹那一套，什么我家先生是最讲究规矩的，不喜欢别人言而无信，等等。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T072547Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T072547Z">
        <seg>While Song Jixin was listening to stories under the old locust tree with Zhi Gui, he was called by someone to go and play go with them. Song Jixin was rather reluctant, but the person who extended the invitation told him that he was there on Mr. Qi's behalf, and that Mr. Qi wanted to see if he had made any improvement in his play. Song Jixin harbored a mixture of indescribable emotions toward the serious and authoritative Mr. Qi. It was a combination of respect and fear. Hence, he had no choice but to accept the invitation, given that it was from Mr. Qi. However, he insisted on staying to hear the end of the story before going to the private school. Thus, the azure-robed young boy who had acted as Mr. Qi's messenger could only return first. Prior to his departure, he urged Song Jixin not to be too late, nagging him with the same old spiel about how Mr. Qi was a man of rules and principles, and that he didn't like it when people were tardy and lacking in punctuality.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪和婢女稚圭只是继续前行。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T205651Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T205651Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin and Zhi Gui continued onward without pause.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪和对面的同龄人，几乎是同时开始学棋，只是宋集薪天资聪颖，棋力进步神速，一日千里，所以被传授两人棋艺的齐先生视为高段者，猜先之时，就由宋集薪先从棋盒中掏出一把白棋，数目不等，秘不示人。青衫少年随后拈出一枚或是两枚黑子，猜对白棋奇偶后，就能够执黑先行，这就有了先行的优势。宋集薪在头两年的对弈当中，无论是执白后行，还是执黑先行，无一败绩。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T074147Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T073318Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin and the young boy across from him had begun learning go almost at the same time, but Song Jixin possessed remarkable aptitude and intelligence that allowed him to make rapid progress. Hence, Mr. Qi, who had taught go to both of them, regarded him as a go player with extremely high potential. To start off the stone guessing minigame, Song Jixin would pull out a handful of white stones of indeterminate number from the box. The azure-robed young boy would then pull out either one or two black stones, and if he could guess whether the number of white stones in Song Jixin's hand was odd or even, then he would receive the black stones and go first, thereby giving him an advantage. In all of the games that they had played against each other in the first two years, Song Jixin had maintained a spotless win record regardless of whether he recieved the black or white stones.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪回过神，笑脸灿烂起来，“不知为何，想起那只死皮赖脸的四脚蛇了，稚圭你想啊，我都把它摔到陈平安的院子了，它依然要往咱们家窜，你说陈平安的狗窝，得是多么不遭人待见，才会寒酸到连一条小蛇都不愿意进去？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T224711Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T224711Z">
        <seg>After returning to his senses, a bright smile appeared on Song Jixin's face. "For some reason, the thought of that tenacious four-legged snake just crossed my mind. Think about it, Zhi Gui. I already threw that thing into Chen Ping'an's yard, yet it still crawled into our home. How terrible of a place must Chen Ping'an's den be if even a little snake didn't want to stay there?"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪在那少年身影消失，才轻声问道：“先生也要离开这里了？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T080623Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T080623Z">
        <seg>Only after the young boy was out of sight did Song Jixin ask in a quiet voice, "Are you about to leave this place as well, Sir?"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪察觉到少女扯了扯自己袖子。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T105802Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T105802Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin felt Zhi Gui tug on his sleeve, and there seemed to be a tacit understanding between them as he immediately knew what she wanted and refrained from articulating what he was about to say next.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪带着婢女稚圭来到老槐树下，发现树荫里人满为患，将近半百号人，坐在自家搬来的板凳椅子上，陆陆续续还有孩童扯着长辈过来凑热闹。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T210538Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T210538Z">
        <seg>After arriving at the locust tree with Zhi Gui, Song Jixin discovered that it was extremely packed, with close to 100 people gathered under the tree's shade. He sat down onto the stool that he had brought over from home, and there were still more children dragging their adult family members to get in on the fun.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪当时挖着耳朵，不厌其烦，说知道了知道了。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T072750Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T072750Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin merely picked at his own ear in an agitated manner, saying something to placate the young boy so that he would go away.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪愣了愣，循着声音转头望去，是个眉眼含笑的锦衣少年，站在院外，一张全然陌生的面孔。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T101214Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T101214Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin was rather startled by the question, and he turned to discover a completely unfamiliar brocade-robed young boy standing outside the courtyard with a faint smile on his face. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪手肘抵在桌面上，托着腮帮，一手双指捻子，轻轻敲击石桌，凝视着棋局。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T080105Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T080105Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin's elbow was resting on the table, while his cheek was resting on his elbow. At the same time, he held a stone in two of his fingers on his other hand, gently tapping the stone table as he stared at the position.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪打了个哈欠。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230526Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T230526Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin gave a bored yawn. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪扯了扯嘴角，“没意思。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T202517Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T202517Z">
        <seg>"What a spoilsport," Song Jixin grumbled with a displeased expression.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪换了一句话说出口，“我和稚圭可能下个月就要离开这里了。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T105851Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T105851Z">
        <seg>Instead, he said something else. "Zhi Gui and I are probably going to be leaving this place next month."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪斜眼道：“卖！怎么不卖！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T101627Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T101627Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin took a glance at the brocade-robed young boy out of the corner of his eye as he replied, "Sure, why not?"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪朝着对面的同龄人挑了一下眉头，笑问道：“要不要让先两棋，否则这家伙肯定输。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T075208Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T075208Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin raised an eyebrow as he glanced at the boy seated across from him, then chuckled, "Should I give him a handicap of a few stones? Otherwise, he's losing this game for sure."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪满脸惊讶，有些尴尬，壮着胆子说道：“先生像是在‘托孤’，让我好不适应。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T082139Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T082139Z">
        <seg>A surprised and slightly awkward look appeared on Song Jixin's face, and he mustered up some courage as he said, "It almost sounds like this is going to be the final time we see each other, and it feels very strange."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪皱眉思索片刻，很快眼前一亮，眉头舒展道：“是棋盘格局变小了。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T074849Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T074849Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin considered the new rules with slightly furrowed brows for a moment, following which eyes quickly lit up as he said, "This is essentially shrinking the board!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪瞥了眼老人，幸灾乐祸道：“咱们小镇识字的没几个，这位说书先生算是媚眼抛给瞎子看了。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T212421Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T212421Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin was looking at the old man with schadenfreude in his eyes as he said, "Barely anyone in our town even knows how to read. This storyteller's efforst are completely wasted here."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪突然开口说道：“稚圭，虽说姓陈的家伙，按照我们读书人老祖宗的说法，属于‘朽木不可雕也，粪土之墙不可圬’，但是不管怎么说，他这辈子总算还是做了一件有意义的事情。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T220813Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T220813Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin suddenly said, "When it comes to Chen Ping'an, my scholar ancestors would say that he's a piece of rotten wood that can't be carved, or a pile of manure that can't be built up into a wall, but at the very least, he's done one meaningful thing in his life."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪笑了，望向南方，露出一抹心神向往，“我听说京城那个地方的藏书，比我们小镇的花草树木还要多！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T225449Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T225449Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin smiled as he cast his gaze toward the south, and a hint of longing appeared on his face. "I heard that there are more books in the capital"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪笑道：“呦，稚圭，监守自盗的意思也懂？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T225603Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T225201Z">
        <seg>"Oh? You know what it means to steal what's entrusted to someone?" Song Jixin asked with a smile.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪笑道：“就是剑。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T212222Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T212222Z">
        <seg>"It's a sword," Song Jixin replied with a smile.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪笑道：“那正好，我还能为先生送行。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T080717Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T080717Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin smiled as he said, "That's good. I'll be able to see you off."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪翻了个白眼，伸出一根手指，晃了晃，“白银一万两！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T101732Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T101732Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin rolled his eyes as he raised a finger and wagged it from side to side. "I want 10,000 silver!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪脸色阴沉。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T101958Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T101958Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin was far from amused.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪自言自语道：“咱们离开小镇后，屋子里的东西交由陈平安照看，这家伙会不会监守自盗啊？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T225454Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T224925Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin mused to himself, "After we leave the town, Chen Ping'an will look after everything in our house. Do you think he'd steal what was entrusted to him?"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪自顾自说道：“陈平安呢，人倒是不坏，就是性子太死板，做什么事情只认死理，所以当了窑匠，意味着他再勤劳苦练，也注定做不出一件有灵气的好东西来，所以刘羡阳的师父，那个姚老头儿，对陈平安死活看不上眼，是有其独到眼光的，这叫朽木不可雕。至于粪土之墙不可圬嘛，大致意思就是说陈平安这种穷酸鬼，哪怕你给他穿上件龙袍，他照样是个土里土气的泥腿子……”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T221416Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T221416Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin continued speaking, almost as if he were talking to himself. "Chen Ping'an is not a bad person, he's just way too dogmatic in his personality. There's no flexibility in the way he does things. That's why after becoming a potter, no matter hard he worked, it was predestined that he would never be able to create a good product with any flair or spark. That's also why Old Man Yao never took a liking to him. He was a man with a keen eye, and he knew that Chen Ping'an simply wasn't cut out of this. That's what it means for him to be a piece of rotten wood that can't be carved. As for a pile of manure that can't be molded into a wall, what that basically means is that for someone meant to be impoverished like Chen Ping'an, even if you dress him up in the emperor's dragon robes, he'll still just be a good-for-nothing hillbilly."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪蓦然哈哈大笑，用手指点了点陈平安，嬉皮笑脸道：“胆小如鼠，难怪寒门无贵子，莫说是这辈子贫贱任人欺，说不定下辈子也逃不掉。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T110210Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin burst into laughter as he poked Chen Ping'an with his finger with a mischievous grin on his face. "You're such a coward! No wonder impoverished families never produce noble sons. Not only are you destined to be bullied and derided by others in this lifetime, you'll probably suffer the same fate in your next life as well!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪被问住了，却不愿露怯，便随口道：“尽是胡说八道，估计看过几本不入流的稗官野史，拿来糊弄乡野村夫的。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T212723Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T212723Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin was stumped by these questions, but he didn't want to look stupid, so he said in a dismissive voice, "It's all nonsense. He probably read a few obscure unofficial historical texts and is regurgitating what he read to swindle uneducated hillbillies."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪见那少年不像是开玩笑的样子，连忙改口道：“是黄金万两！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T101918Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T101918Z">
        <seg>The boy didn't appear to be joking, and Song Jixin hurriedly amended, "Actually, I want 20,000 gold!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪说到这里的时候，自嘲道：“我其实比陈平安还惨。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T221445Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T221445Z">
        <seg>A self-deprecating look appeared on Song Jixin's face here, and he sighed, "I'm actually even more pitiful than him."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪起身笑道：“好嘞。那这棋局就劳烦先生收拾喽。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T082405Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T082349Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin rose to his feet as he chuckled, "Alright, then I'll have to trouble you to clean up the board, Sir."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪转头望去，突然愣住了。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T213202Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T213202Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin turned to look at her, and he was abruptly transfixed.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>宋集薪还从书上听说一个小镇没有的习俗，所以在稚圭十二岁那年，他便买了小镇最好的新酿之酒，搬出那只偷藏而来的瓷瓶，釉色极美，犹如青梅，把酒倒入其中后，将其小心泥封，最后埋入地下。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T220635Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T220635Z">
        <seg>Song Jixin had also read about a tradition that didn't exist in the town from a book. Hence, when Zhi Gui was 12 years old, he bought the best newly brewed win in the town, then brought out the porcelain vase that he had hid away. The coloration of the vast was extremely beautiful, resembling a greengage, and he poured the win into the vase before carefully sealing it in clay and burying it underground.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>对于一名天人境的强者来说，需要花十秒钟才能去肯定一件事情，这绝对不可思议之极，但也同样证明发生在他身上的事情有多么得不可思议。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Yuanl" changedate="20230318T054855Z" creationid="Yuanl" creationdate="20230318T054855Z">
        <seg>we reply on thios</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>对于下棋，才华横溢的宋集薪，好不好玩，有不有趣，才是首选。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T075713Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T075713Z">
        <seg>Despite his superb aptitude, Song Jixin top priority in playing go had always been to have fun.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>对于青衫少年，从第一次捻子落于棋盘，他就执着于胜负二字。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T075742Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T075742Z">
        <seg>In contrast, from the moment the azure-robed young boy first picked up a go stone, he had always been fixated on the concepts of winning and losing.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>对陈平安没好气说道：“你那点破烂事，等会儿再说。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T165354Z">
        <seg>"We'll discuss your shitty job later," the man said to Chen Ping'an in a disgruntled voice.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>对陈平安随口说道：“对了，方才我经过老槐树的时候，那边多了个自称说书人的老头儿，正在那边摆弄摊子，还说他积攒了一肚子的奇人趣事，要跟咱们念叨念叨，你有空可以去瞅瞅。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T123328Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T123328Z">
        <seg>After dropping the facade, he casually said to Chen Ping'an, "By the way, as I was passing by the old locust tree earlier, I met an old man who set up a new stall over there. He told me that he's a storyteller, and that he has a bunch of interesting stories that he wants to tell us. You can go and take a look there in your free time."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>对面少年顿时面红耳赤，嚅嚅喏喏，因为他心知肚明，自己获胜次数越来越多，除了棋力增长之外，其实真正的主要原因是宋集薪，这两年下棋越来越心不在焉，甚至有些不厌其烦了，很多胜负手，宋集薪甚至故意放水，或是先手布局明明占优后，棋至中盘，宋集薪会刻意为了屠大龙而兵行险着。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T075633Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T075633Z">
        <seg>The young boy immediately became flushed with embarrassment upon hearing this. He knew in his heart that the reason he was able to improve his winning record against Song Jixin was not just attributable to his own improvement. Instead, the main reason was because Song Jixin had become less and less interested in the game over the past couple of years, to the point that he was beginning to hate the game. There were many instances in which he had intentionally thrown games, or taken major risks in the middlegame after he had already secured a clear advantage in the early game, trying to secure flashy wins, only to lose the games in the process.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>小镇不大不小，六百多户人家，镇上穷苦人家的门户，陈平安大多认得，至于家底殷实的有钱人家，门槛高，泥腿子少年可跨不进去，一些个大户扎堆的宽敞巷弄，陈平安甚至都没有踏足过，那边的街道，多铺以大块大块的青石板，下雨天，绝不会一脚踩下去泥浆四溅。那些质地极佳的青石板，经过千百年来人马车辆的踩踏碾压，早已摩挲得光滑如镜。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T173436Z">
        <seg>The town wasn't very large, home to fewer than 700 families, and Chen Ping'an knew the majority of the impoverished families in the town. As for the weathy families, they were too far above a poor hillbilly like him. In fact, Chen Ping'an hadn't even set foot on any of the wide and spacious alleys where some of the wealthy families resided in clusters. Those streets were mostly paved with large bluestone slabs so there was no risk of having to slosh through mud even on rainy days. After centuries of being trodden on by people, horses, and carriages, the high-quality bluestone slabs had already been polished to the point that they were as smooth as mirrors.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>小镇外人来往得不多，照理说，如今官窑烧制这棵摇钱树都倒了，就更加不会有新面孔。姚老头在世的时候，曾经有次喝高了，就跟陈平安和刘羡阳这些徒弟说，咱们做的是天底下独一份的官窑生意，是给皇帝陛下和皇后娘娘的御用瓷器，其他老百姓哪怕再有钱，哪怕当的官再大，胆敢沾碰，那可都是要被砍头的。那天的姚老头，精神气格外不一样。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T145954Z">
        <seg>There weren't many outsiders who visited the town. Now that the town had been deprived of a major source of income in the form of the official kilns, it stood to reason that there would be even fewer visitors from outside. Back when Old Man Yao was around, there was one time when he had a little too much to drink, and he told his disciples, including Chen Ping'an and Liu Xianyang, that they were the only ones under the heavens manning official kilns, that the chinaware that they produced was imperial ware used by the emperor and the empress, that no matter how rich or lofty in official status someone was, they would be beheaded if they dared to use imperial ware themselves. On that day, Old Man Yao had seemed like a completely different person.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>小镇并无城墙环绕，毕竟别说流寇匪徒，就是小偷蟊贼都少有，所以名义上是城门，其实就是一排东倒西歪的老旧栅栏，马马虎虎有那么个让行人车辆通过的地方，就算是这座小镇的脸面了。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T145219Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T135110Z">
        <seg>The town wasn't surrounded by any walls, so even bandits and gangs were a problem, let alone petty thieves. The so-called town gate was actually nothing more than a row of old and uneven fencing materials, acting as nothing than a makeshift checkpoint for people and carriages to pass through in order to keep up appearances for the town.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>小镇没有什么大人物，也没有什么风浪，故而被朝廷派驻此地的窑务督造官，无疑就是戏本上的那种青天大老爷，在历史上数十位督造官中，又以上任督造官宋大人，最得民心，宋大人不像之前那些高高在上的官老爷，宋大人不但没有躲在官署，修身养气，也没有闭门谢客，一心在书斋治学，而是对官窑瓷器的烧造事宜，事必躬亲，简直比匠户窑工更像是乡野百姓，十余年间，这位原本满身书卷气的宋大人，肌肤被晒得黝黑发亮，平日里装束与庄稼汉无异，待人接物，从无架子，只可惜小镇龙窑烧造而出的御用瓷器，无论是釉色品相，还是大器小件的形制，始终不尽如人意，准确说来，比起以往水准，甚至还要稍逊一筹，让老窑头们百思不得其解。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T222949Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T222949Z">
        <seg>There weren't any important figures in the town, nor were there any exciting events. Hence, the kiln supervision official sent by the imperial court naturally became the most prominent figure in the town, much like the all-powerful decision makers seen in stageplays. Out of the dozens of kiln supervision officials that had been assigned to the town throughout history, Master Song was the most popular with the people. He wasn't like the high and mighty officials that came before him. He didn't hide away in his official manor to work on personal cultivation, nor did he turn away all visitors and focus solely on reading and self-education. Instead, he always attended to matters related to the creation of imperial ware in person, and he was even more like a commoner than the potters working at the kilns. During the dozen or so years in which he was at the town, his original scholarly appearance had been replaced by a dark tan, and his regular attire was no different from what was worn by the men working in the fields. He never put on a high and mighty front when dealing with others, but unfortunately, the imperial ware fired using the dragon kilns in the town were never quite up to standard, regardless of whether it was in terms of shape and form, or their coloration and glaze. In fact, the imperial ware that was produced had regressed compared with before, much to the puzzlement of the old kiln masters. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>小镇没谁把这个家伙当回事。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T165425Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T165425Z">
        <seg>No one in the town held any respect for him, but he was the one who decided whether outsiders could enter the town or not.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>小院内外，仿佛有一双蟒蛟在对峙。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T084136Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T084136Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少女依然迷迷糊糊的模样。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T082941Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T082941Z">
        <seg>Meanwhile, Zhi Gui was still seemingly dazed and confused, as innocent and naive as ever.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少女此时就站在院墙那边，她有一双杏眼，怯怯弱弱。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T100956Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T100956Z">
        <seg>At this moment, Zhi Gui was standing on the other side of the wall with a timid look in her large, round eyes.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少女瞪大眼眸，满脸匪夷所思，像一头惊慌失措的年幼麋鹿。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T101705Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T101705Z">
        <seg>Zhi Gui's eyes widened with incredulity upon hearing this exchange, making her resemble a panicked deerling.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少女立即踮起脚尖，乖巧回了一句，“哎，好的，公子。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T085403Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T085403Z">
        <seg>"Yes, Young Master," Zhi Gui immediately replied obediently as she got up on the tips of her toes.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少女缓缓收敛脸上的无辜神色，眼神逐渐冷冽，嘴角挂起讥讽笑意。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T084107Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T084107Z">
        <seg>The innocent look on the young girl's face slowly faded, and a cold look appeared in her eyes while a mocking sneer surfaced on her face, as if she were asking "what're you gonna do about it?"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少年一头雾水。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T171851Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an was still none the wiser.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少年不信邪，几次辗转腾挪，最后仍是没能抓住槐叶。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230813Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T230813Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an refused to give up, making a few more attempts, but was ultimately unable to catch the leaf, much to his dismay.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少年与她心有灵犀，下意识就将已经到了嘴边的话语，重新咽回肚子。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T105802Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T105802Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少年低头看着脚上的草鞋，突然就笑了起来。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T203408Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T203408Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an looked down at the straw sandals on his feet, and smile suddenly appeared on his face.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少年只好安静望向东边的宽阔大路，蜿蜒而漫长，像一条粗壮的黄色长蛇。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T232115Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T232115Z">
        <seg>Hence, he could only cast his gaze toward the wide path in the east in silence. It was a long and winding road that resembled a thick yellow snake.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少年姓陈，名平安，爹娘早逝。小镇的瓷器极负盛名，本朝开国以来，就担当起“奉诏监烧献陵祭器”的重任，有朝廷官员常年驻扎此地，监理官窑事务。无依无靠的少年，很早就当起了烧瓷的窑匠，起先只能做些杂事粗活，跟着一个脾气糟糕的半路师傅，辛苦熬了几年，刚刚琢磨到一点烧瓷的门道，结果世事无常，小镇突然失去了官窑造办这张护身符，小镇周边数十座形若卧龙的窑炉，一夜之间全部被官府勒令关闭熄火。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T075110Z">
        <seg>The young boy's name was Chen Ping'an, and both his parents had passed away at a very early stage in his life. The town that he lived in was extremely renowned for producing chinaware. Ever since the founding of the nation, the town had taken on the important task of producing chinaware to be offered to the imperial court, and there were imperial officials constantly stationed in the town, overseeing the operation of the official kilns. Without any parents to rely on, Chen Ping'an became a potter at a very young age. In the beginning, he was only able to perform some menial tasks and manual labor, toiling away arduously for several years under a reluctant master with a terrible temper. In a cruel twist of fate, just when he had begun to grasp some of the basics of pottery firing, the town suddenly lost the right to host official kilns. Over the course of just a single night, all of the dozens of coiling-dragon-like kilns throughout the town were ordered to be shut down by the authorities.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少年家世贫穷，没有读过书，但是明白一个书本外的道理，世上除了爹娘，再没有人是理所应当对你好的。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T070121Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T070121Z">
        <seg>He came from a very impoverished background and had never received an education, but he understood a principle that wasn't taught in books, which was that aside from your parents, no one in the world had a duty to be good to you, and his parents had passed away very early in his life.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少年怔怔出神。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T015949Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an raised his head to find that the sun was only just beginning to rise in the east, and he was momentarily dazed.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少年欢快跑去。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T082410Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T082410Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少年毫无征兆地转过头，向年轻道人远远抛来一颗铜钱，灿烂笑道：“借你吉言！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T205925Z">
        <seg>All of a sudden, Song Jixin turned around without any warning before tossing the taoist priest a copper coin from afar with a bright smile. "Thanks for your blessings!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少年腼腆笑了笑，摇摇头，跑着离去。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T005356Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an shook his head with a bashful smile in response before jogging away.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少年自然不清楚这些奥妙玄机，一路脚步轻盈，来到那座乡塾馆舍外，附近竹林郁郁，绿意欲滴。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T015700Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T015700Z">
        <seg>He jogged lightly to the private school, and there was a lush and vibrant bamboo forest nearby.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少年至今仍然清晰记得，那个只肯认自己做半个徒弟的老师傅，姓姚，在去年暮秋时分的清晨，被人发现坐在一张小竹椅子上，正对着窑头方向，闭眼了。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T085815Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T085815Z">
        <seg>He could still clearly recall that his old master was a man with the surname of Yao, and he had only been willing to accept him as half a disciple. One late autumn morning the previous year, he was discovered to have passed away peacefully while seated on a small bamboo chair, facing the kiln with his eyes closed.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少年跑出去很远后，鬼使神差地转头回望。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T020954Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T020954Z">
        <seg>After a while, he was struck by the urge to turn back for some reason, even though he was already very far away from the school.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少年郑重其事地接过那张符纸，小心翼翼珍藏起来后，没有忘记把五枚铜钱放在桌案上，鞠躬致谢。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T014409Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an accepted the talisman with a solemn expression, then carefully stowed it away as if it were a priceless treasure. He then placed five copper coins down onto the table before bowing in gratitude.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少年陈平安无可奈何。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230813Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T230813Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>少年陈平安的确没见过世面，但不等于看不懂脸色。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T170925Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an didn't have much life experience, but he wasn't so clueless that he couldn't read faces.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>就在此时，一个头发乱糟糟的中年汉子猛然打开门，对着陈平安骂骂咧咧道：“小王八蛋，是不是掉钱眼里了？这么早就来催命叫魂，你赶着投胎去见你死鬼爹娘啊？！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T164159Z">
        <seg>Right at this moment, a middle-aged man with a head of disheveled hair abruptly opened the gate, then erupted into a loud tirade directed at Chen Ping'an. "How desperate for money are you, you little bastard? Who in their right mind would come here at such an ungodly hour? Are you rushing off to reunite with your dead parents?!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>就在此时，一只小巧玲珑的黄雀，从高空飞扑到桌面上，轻啄了一下某颗铜钱，很快便没了兴致，振翅远去。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T014601Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T014601Z">
        <seg>Right at this moment, a small oriole flew down from the sky onto the table, gently pecking one of the copper coins before quickly losing interest and flying away again.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>就在此时，说书先生正说道：“世上虽已无真龙，龙之从属，如蛟、虬、螭等等，仍是真真正正、实实在在活在人世间，说不定就……”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230150Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T230150Z">
        <seg>Right at this moment, the storyteller declared, "There are no longer any true dragons left in the world, but dragonkin such as wyrms, drakes, and hornless dragons. They truly exist among us in this world, and perhaps..."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>就在此时，道人眼前一亮，赶紧闭上眼睛，朗声道：“池塘盈满蛙声乱，刺人肚肠是人心。此处功名水上萍，只宜风动四方行！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T205305Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T205305Z">
        <seg>Right at this moment, his eyes suddenly lit up, and he hurriedly closed his eyes as he recited, "One often blames external distractions for spoiling their peace, but the true distraction comes from within. Achievements are nothing more than lilypads on water, going whichever way the wind blows."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>平时最喜欢恪守规矩的青衫少年，听闻“噩耗”后，目瞪口呆，痴痴看着棋盘，最后小心翼翼说道：“先生，如此一来，好像很多定势用不上了。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T074813Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T074813Z">
        <seg>The azure-robed young boy always liked to abide by the rules, so this sudden change was nothing short of a nightmare for him. He stared at the board with a dazed expression, then said in a careful voice, "Mr. Qi, if play like this, then there are many sets of jōseki that we won't be able to use." [ref]In go and shōgi, a jōseki or jouseki is the studied sequences of moves for which the result is considered balanced for both black and white sides.[/ref]</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>年轻道人不露声色地瞥了眼女子，视线微微向下，是一幅鼓囊囊的风景，然后道士咽了咽口水，说了一句神叨叨的卦语，“今日贫道给自己算了一签，下签，大凶啊。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T091044Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T091020Z">
        <seg>The daoist priest took a subtle glance at the woman, but as he shifted his gaze slightly downward, he was greeted by the sight of a voluptuous bulge. He gulped slightly, then said in a mysterious voice, "I picked out a slip myself earlier today, and it was a bad slip that entails great peril."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>年轻道人也不恼火，对那高大少年大声喊道：“指望今年百事昌，谁知命里有祸殃。无灾不肯念神仙，欲得安稳当烧香应当烧香啊”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T204231Z">
        <seg>The young taoist priest remained calm and collected as he yelled out, "Everyone hopes for fortune and prosperity, but who knows what troubles life has in store? People only turn to the gods when things go wrong, but to have a safe and stable life, one should regularly offer burning incense to the gods."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>年轻道人咳嗽一声，板起脸，继续守株待兔，等待下一位客人。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T015308Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T015308Z">
        <seg>He then cleared his throat and put on a serious expression, waiting for his next customer.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>年轻道人将这枚铜钱轻轻放在桌上。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T210136Z">
        <seg>The taoist priest gently placed the copper coin down onto the table, and all of a sudden, an oriole quickly flew down onto the table, gently pecking at the copper coin before picking it up with its beak. It then looked up at the taoist priest with a pair of bright and intelligent eyes that were no different from a human's.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>年轻道人抱拳作揖，求情讨饶。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T204614Z">
        <seg>The young taoist priest could cup his fist and bow as he begged for mercy.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>年轻道人挥挥手，示意少年忙自己的事情去。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T014430Z">
        <seg>The taoist priest waved a dismissive hand, indicating that Chen Ping'an was free to go, and he immediately rushed away to deliver the final letter.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>年轻道人摇头道：“贫道行事，童叟无欺，说好了解签加写符一起，收你五钱的。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T013114Z">
        <seg>The young taoist priest shook his head in response. "I never go back on my word. I promised that I was going to give you a fortune reading and a yellow paper talisman for five copper coins."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>年轻道人环顾四周，最后视线停留在远处那座高高的牌坊楼，恰好对着“气冲斗牛”四字匾额，感慨道：“可惜了。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T210304Z">
        <seg>The taoist priest swept his gaze over his surroundings, and in the end, his eyes settled on the tall archway in the distance. He just so happened to be facing the plaque that read "unmatched aura", and he mused, "What a pity."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>年轻道人看到快步跑过的少年后，赶紧打招呼道：“年轻人，走过路过不要错过，来抽一支签，贫道帮你算上一卦，可以帮你预知吉凶福祸。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T010734Z">
        <seg>Right as Chen Ping'an was jogging past, the young taoist priest hurriedly called out to him. "Don't miss out on a reading, young man. Pick out a slip and I'll tell your fortune. I can help you predict whether fortune or peril awaits you."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>年轻道人等到高大少年走远，才敢重新落座，叹了口气，“世道艰辛，人心不古，害得贫道也糊口不易啊。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T204827Z">
        <seg>Only after Liu Xianyang had gone far away did the taoist priest dare to return to his seat, and he sighed, "These are difficult times. People are no longer as kind and accepting as they used to be, and it's getting harder and harder to make a living."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>当了一段时间飘来荡去的孤魂野鬼，少年实在找不到挣钱的营生，靠着那点微薄积蓄，少年勉强填饱肚子，前几天听说几条街外的骑龙巷，来了个姓阮的外乡老铁匠，对外宣称要收七八个打铁的学徒，不给工钱，但管饭，陈平安就赶紧跑去碰运气，不曾想老人只是斜瞥了他一眼，就把他拒之门外，当时陈平安就纳闷，难道打铁这门活计，不是看臂力大小，而是看面相好坏？</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T092155Z">
        <seg>After drifting around aimlessly for a while, he was unable to find any sources of income. He was only just barely able to feed himself with his meager savings, and a few days ago, he heard that a foreign blacksmith with the surname of Ruan had arrived in Dragon Riding Alley, an alley that was a few streets away. The old blacksmith had declared that he was planning to take seven or eight disciples, and no wages were provided, but meals were ensured. Chen Ping'an had immediately gone to try his luck, but to his dismay, the old blacksmith only took a side glance at him before turning him away. At the time, Chen Ping'an had felt quite perplexed. Could it be that blacksmithing didn't rely on the strength of one's arm, but the charm of one's looks instead?</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>当宋集薪带着稚圭来到学塾后院，凉风习习，文质彬彬的青衫少年郎如往常一般，已经坐在了南边的凳子上，腰杆挺直，正襟危坐。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T072901Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T072901Z">
        <seg>As Song Jixin arrived in the yard behind the private school, there was a cool breeze, and as usual, the scholarly azure-robed young boy was already seated on the stool to the south with a serious expression and his back ramrod straight.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>当时的宋集薪全然不怕，反而乐滋滋地蹲在墙头上看热闹，唯恐天下不乱。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T033118Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T033118Z">
        <seg>At the time, not only was Song Jixin not frightened by this horrific scene, he was watching with glee as he squatted on top of the wall, reveling in the chaos of the situation.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>怎么会不记得，简直就是记忆犹新。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T104631Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T104631Z">
        <seg>Not only did he remember it, it was a very clear memory in his mind.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>想着还是去城东门讨债一次的少年，在临近老槐树的时候，也看到了眼前有槐叶飘落，只是他加快步子，想要伸手去接住。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230713Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T230713Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an was considering whether he should go to the eastern town gate to ask for the five copper coins that he was owed, and he also saw a locust leave fluttering down as he approached the old locust tree. He immediately sped up in his footsteps and reached out to try and catch the leaf, but the leaf glanced past his hand, carried away by a gentle breeze.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>所以若是逢年过节，纯粹为了讨个好彩头，小镇百姓花上十钱，也能接受，可真遇上烦心事，肯定不会有人愿意来这里当冤大头。若说这个道士是彻头彻尾的骗子，倒也冤枉了人家，小镇就这么大，如果真只会装神弄鬼、坑蒙拐骗，早就给人撵了出去。所以说这位年轻道人的功力，肯定不在相术、解签两事上。倒是有些小病小灾，很多人喝了道人的一碗符水，很快就能痊愈，颇为灵验。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T013020Z">
        <seg>Hence, whenever there was a festival, the residents of the town willing to fork out 10 copper coins for a fortune reading purely for the sake of good fortune. However, no one experiencing any actual troubles would be willing to come here just to be scalped. It would be unfair to say that the taoist priest was a complete an utter fraud. The town was not a very large place, and if all he did was intentionally confuse and defraud people, then he would've been kicked out long ago. Hence, it was clear that the young taoist priest's forte wasn't his fortune telling. Instead, he had made a name for himself through his amulet water, which had consistently cured many of the town's residents of various minor ailments over the years.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>按照小镇的习俗，女子嫁人时，便会有聘请一位父母子女皆健在的福气齐全人，请她绞去新娘脸上的绒毛，剪齐额发和鬓角，谓之开面，或是升眉。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T213643Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T213643Z">
        <seg>According to the traditions of the town, whenever a woman was married, an individual with a full set of blessings would be invited. The definition of such an individual was one whose parents and children were all still alive, and that person would be invited to shave off the fine hairs on the bride's face, as well as to trim her bangs and temples. The procedure was known as face opening, or brow elevating.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>按照这座小镇传承数百年的风俗，如果有蛇类往自家屋子钻，是好兆头，主人绝对不要将其驱逐打杀。宋集薪在正月初一的时候，坐在门槛上晒太阳，然后就有只俗称四脚蛇的小玩意儿，在他的眼皮子底下往屋里窜，宋集薪一把抓住就往院子里摔出去，不曾想那条已经摔得七荤八素的四脚蛇，愈挫愈勇，一次次，把从来不信鬼神之说的宋集薪给气得不行，一怒之下就把它甩到了陈平安院子，哪里想到，宋集薪第二天就在自己床底下，看到了那条盘踞蜷缩起来的四脚蛇。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T105100Z">
        <seg>According to the customs and traditions that had been passed down for several centuries in the small town, it was a good omen for ophidian creatures to make their way into one's home, and it was considered to be extremely taboo for the owners of such fortunate homes to chase out or kill said creatures. On the first day of the first month on the lunar calendar, Song Jixin had been sunbathing while sitting on his doorstep when a creature colloquially known as a four-legged snake began to scurry into the house right under his nose. [ref]The four-legged snake here refers to a gecko.[/ref] Song Jixin grabbed the creature before throwing it out of the yard, but to his surprise, even though the creature was battered and disoriented from the fall, it seemed to only grow more and more courageous with each failure, attempting to crawl into the house over and over again. Song Jixin had never been one to believe in superstitions, and he was so infuriated by the persistent creature that he threw it into Chen Ping'an's yard in a fit of rage. Much to his bewilderment, he discovered that very same four-legged snake laying curled up under his bed the very next day.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>按照齐先生的规矩，双方对弈，投子无声认输即可，绝对不可言“我输了”三字。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T080158Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T080158Z">
        <seg>According to the rules set by Mr. Qi, it was strictly prohibited to verbally declare one's loss, and resignation took place in the form the silence gesture of tossing one's stones onto the table.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>按照齐先生订立下来的老规矩，宋集薪和青衫郎要猜子，执黑先行。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T073351Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T073154Z">
        <seg>According to the rules set by Mr. Qi, Song Jixin and the azure-robed young boy had to play a minigame of guessing the stones, and the one who received teh black stones would get to go first.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>接下来青衫少年落子缓慢，谨小慎微，步步为营。宋集薪依旧是落子如飞，大开大合，羚羊挂角。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T075859Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T075859Z">
        <seg>During the game, the azure-robed young boy played each turn slowly and carefully, steadily building a foundation, while Song Jixin was playing just as rapidly as usual, going for large and expansive positions.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>搁下笔，提起那张符纸，年轻道人吹了吹墨迹，“拿回家后，人站在门槛内，将黄纸烧在门槛外，就行了。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T014320Z">
        <seg>The young taoist priest set down his brush before picking up the talisman, then blew on it to dry the ink. "Take this home, and all you have to do is burn this outside your doorstep while standing inside your doorstep."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>春风和煦，竹叶摇曳，如翻书声。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T090515Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T090515Z">
        <seg>The spring breeze was as gentle as ever, and the rustling of the bamboo leaves resembled the sound of a book's turning pages.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>暮色里，小镇名叫泥瓶巷的僻静地方，有位孤苦伶仃的清瘦少年，此时他正按照习俗，一手持蜡烛，一手持桃枝，照耀房梁、墙壁、木床等处，用桃枝敲敲打打，试图借此驱赶蛇蝎、蜈蚣等，嘴里念念有词，是这座小镇祖祖辈辈传下来的老话：二月二，烛照梁，桃打墙，人间蛇虫无处藏。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T100205Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T074945Z">
        <seg>In the darkness of the night, there was a thin and lonesome young boy in a secluded place by the name of Clay Vase Alley. At this moment, he was following the traditions of the area, holding a candle in one hand and a peach branch in the other. The young boy was using the candle to illuminate the ceiling, the walls, and the wooden bed in the room, and simultaneously, he was tapping the peach branch around to try and drive away creatures like snakes, scorpions, and centipedes.At the same time, he was chanting an old mantra that had been passed down in the small town for generation upon generation: "On the second day of the second month, the candle illuminates the ceiling, while the peach branch taps the walls, leaving no place for snake and insects to hide."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>最后一位曾经在此算姻缘的新嫁妇人，路过此地，眼见着年轻道人如此反常，羞羞涩涩停下脚步，嗓音软糯，嘴上问着问题，那双会说话的水润眼眸，却在年轻道人的英俊脸庞上使劲徘徊。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T090842Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T090842Z">
        <seg>A newly wed woman who had last had her fortune told there was passing by, and she could see that the young daoist priest wasn't his normal self. She stopped in her tracks in a shy manner and began asking questions in a tender voice, but her large, watery eyes were saying something else entirely as they roamed insistently over the young man's handsome face.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>最后刘羡阳伸出拇指，指了指自己胸膛，趾高气昂道：“阮师傅传授我拳法的时候，我有些想法心得，便与他说了闲话，比如我对姚老头制瓷的独门绝学跳刀的感悟，阮师傅夸我是百年一遇的练武奇才。以后你只管跟着我混，少不了你吃香的喝辣的！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T122825Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T122825Z">
        <seg>Finally, Liu Xianyang pointed at his own chest with his thumb as he declared in a high and mighty manner, "While Master Ruan was teaching me fist techniques, I developed some theories and insights, so I spoke to him about some things, such as my understanding of the jumping blade, which was Old Man Yao's trump card technique in porcelain making. Master Ruan praised me, saying that I'm a generational martial arts talent. As long as you stick with me, you'll be living the good life for sure!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>最后大概朝廷那边觉得兢兢业业的宋大人，没有功劳也有苦劳，将其调回京城的吏部敕令文书上，好歹得了个良的考评。宋大人在返京之前，竟然千金散尽，出资建造了一座廊桥，后来发现宋大人离去车队当中，没有捎带某个孩子后，小镇几个大姓门庭便恍然大悟。可以说，宋大人与小镇积攒下过一份不俗的香火情，加上现任督造官的刻意照拂，少年宋集薪这些年在小镇的生活，衣食无忧，逍遥自在。如今改名为稚圭的丫鬟，关于她的身世来历，众说纷纭，住在泥瓶巷的当地人，说是一个鹅毛大雪的冬天，有个外地女孩沿路乞讨至此，昏死在宋集薪家的院门口，如果不是有人发现的早，就要去阎王爷那边转世投胎了。官署那边做杂事的老人，有另外的说法，信誓旦旦说是宋大人早年让人从别地买下的孤儿，为的就是给私生子宋集薪物色一个知冷暖的体己人，弥补一下父子不得相认的亏欠。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T224033Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T224033Z">
        <seg>In the end, the imperial court most likely felt like Master Song's efforts were very commendable, even though the outcome wasn't ideal, and he was given a decent evaluation on the documentation from the Ministry of Personnel summoning him back to the capital. Prior to returning to the capital, Master Song spent all of his money to fund the construction of a covered bridge. After that, it was discovered that a certain child wasn't brought along on the convoy that Master Song had departed in, and the most affluent families in the town immediately realized what this entailed. It could be said that Master Song had accumulated a great deal of good karma in the town, and in addition to that, Song Jixin was being looked after by Master Song's kiln supervision official successor, so he didn't have to worry about food, clothing, or shelter, and led a carefree life. As for his maidservant, whose name had been changed to Zhi Gui, there were many different theories and stories about her origins. The local residents of Clay Vase Alley claimed that she was a little beggar from out of town that had come to this place on a snowy winter's day. She had fallen unconcious in front of hte entrance of Song Jixin's courtyard, and if she hadn't been discovered in time, she would've already passed on to the afterlife. The old man taking care of menial chores at the official manor had a different story. He proclaimed with great confidence that she was an orphan that Master Song had purchased quite some time ago so that his illegitimate son, Song Jixin, would have an intimitate companion, and that he had done this to compensate for leaving his son behind.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>最后视线，由高到低，由远及近，凝视着街道两旁的桃树，貌似老朽昏聩的老人，这才挤出一丝笑意。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T005628Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T005628Z">
        <seg>He looked up, then down, then peered into the distance before withdrawing his gaze, staring at the peach trees that lined the street, following which a faint smile appeared on his face.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>最后道人补上一句，“若是能拿到外边去卖，怎么都有千八百两银子吧？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T210330Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T210330Z">
        <seg>He then added, "If I could take this outside to sell, surely it would fetch at least 800 to 1,000 taels of silver."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>最后闭眼，再睁开眼，可能就是下辈子的事情了。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T203352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T203352Z">
        <seg>After closing one's eyes for the final time, the next time one reopened their eyes, they could be in the next life already.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>有个头戴古怪高冠的年轻人，身材修长，腰间悬有一块绿色玉佩，他似乎等得不耐烦了，独自走出人群，就想要去推开本就无锁的栅栏大门，只是在他手指就要触碰到木门的时候，他突然猛然停下，缓缓收回手，双手负后，笑眯眯望向门内的草鞋少年，也不说话，就是笑。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T163610Z">
        <seg>There was a young man wearing a strange tall hat in the group. He was tall and slim with a green jade pendant hanging from his waist, and he seemed to have grown tired of waiting. The gate had no lock, and he emerged from the crowd on his own as if he were going to push it open, but right as his finger was about to come into contact with the gate, he suddenly stopped before slowly withdrawing his hand, then clasped his hands behind his back as he cast his gaze toward Chen Ping'an with a smile on his face. He didn't say anything, all he did was smile.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>有钱人家就是讲究多，卢家宅子大不说，门口还摆放两尊石狮子，等人高，气势凌人。宋集薪说这玩意儿能够避凶镇邪，陈平安根本不清楚何谓凶邪，只是很好奇等人高的狮子嘴里，好像还含着一粒圆滚滚的石球，这又是如何雕琢出来的？陈平安强忍住去触摸石球的冲动，走上台阶，扣响那个青铜狮子门首，很快就有个年轻人开门走出，一听说是来送信的，那人面无表情，用双指捻住信封一角，接过那封家书后，便转身快步走入宅子，重重关上贴有彩绘财神像的大门。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T005124Z">
        <seg>Wealthy families were very particular about many things. Not only was the Lu Manor massive, there were two stone lions placed on either side of the entrance, both of which were as tall as a grown man, presenting a rather intimidating sight to behold. According to Song Jixin, these things were capable of warding off malicious and evil entities. Chen Ping'an had no idea what these malicious and evil entities were supposed to be. He was only very intrigued by the round stond ball that each of the stone lions held in their mouths, wondering how those balls had been sculpted. He forcibly suppressed the urge to touch those stone balls, then made his way up the steps before using the bronze lion head knockers on the doors. A young man quickly made his way out of the manor, and upon hearing that Chen Ping'an was here to deliver a letter, the man pinched a corner of the letter between two of his fingers and took it from Chen Ping'an in an expressionless manner. He then quickly strode back into the manor before closing the doors, which bore a colorful visage of the god of wealth.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>杏花巷有口水井，名叫铁锁井，一根粗如青壮手臂的铁链，年复一年，垂挂于井口内，何时有此水井有此铁锁，又是何人做此无聊事奇怪事，早已无人知晓真相，就连小镇岁数最大的老人，也说不出个子丑寅卯来。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T091327Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T091327Z">
        <seg>There was a well in Apricot Blossom Alley by the name of Iron Lock Well. A metal chain that was as thick as a young man's arm was dangling down inside the well, and no one knew why the chain was there, nor who had done something as strange and pointless as hanging a chain in the well. Even the oldest individuals in the town were unable to provide any accounts.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>桌案上，笔墨砚纸早就备好，道人仔细问过了陈平安爹娘的姓名籍贯生辰，抽出一张黄色符纸，很快就写完，一气呵成。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T014204Z">
        <seg>A set of writing tools and paper had already been prepared on the table, and the taoist priest carefully enquired Chen Ping'an about the names, birthplaces, and birth dates and times of his parents, then pulled out a yellow paper talisman before quickly inscribing something onto it.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>此人是陈平安的老邻居，据说更是前任监造大人的私生子，那位大人唯恐清流非议、言官弹劾，最后孤身返回京城述职，把孩子交由颇有私交情谊的接任官员，帮着看管照拂。如今小镇莫名其妙地失去官窑烧制资格，负责替朝廷监理窑务的督造大人，自己都泥菩萨过江自身难保了，哪里还顾得上官场同僚的私生子，丢下一些银钱，就火急火燎赶往京城打点关系。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T095754Z">
        <seg>The boy was an old neighbor of Chen Ping'an's, and it was said that he was an illegitimate son of the former kiln supervision official. That official had returned to the capital for a debriefing for fear of being impeached by imperial censors, and he had left his illegitimate son to be looked after by his successor, who was a rather close friend of his. Now that the town had inexplicably lost the right to produce imperial ware, the kiln supervision official responsible for overseeing the operation of the official kilns was left without a job, and he had no interest in continuing to look after the illegitimate son of an imperial court colleague. After leaving some money behind, he hurriedly traveled to the capital to salvage his relations with powerful figures.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>此时陈平安和那些外乡人，双方隔着一道木栅栏，两两相望。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T150521Z">
        <seg>At this moment, Chen Ping'an and these outsiders were looking across at each other, separated by the makeshift gate.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>此时陈平安绕着十二脚牌坊跑了一圈，每一面都有四个大字，字体古怪，显得各不相同，分别是“当仁不让”，“希言自然”，“莫向外求”和“气冲斗牛”。听宋集薪说，除了某四个字，其余三处匾额石刻，都曾被涂抹、篡改过。陈平安对这些懵懵懂懂，从未深思，当然，就算少年想要刨根问底，也是徒劳，他连宋集薪经常挂在嘴边的地方县志，到底是什么书都不知道。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T143959Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an ran a lap around the 12-pillar archway, and each side bore four large characters inscribed in strange fonts, all of which appeared to be different from one another. The inscriptions read "doing my part", "comply with the natural order", "refrain from looking outward", and "unmatched aura". According to Song Jixin, one of those inscriptions, all three of the other incscriptions had been smeared or altered at some point. Chen Ping'an was quite clueless about these matters, and he had never given this notion much deep thought. Of course, even if he wanted to get to unearth some answers, he wouldn't have been able to. Even now, he still didn't know what kind of book the Local County Chronicles that Song Jixin frequently mentioned was supposed to be.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>死死盯住那对爷孙愈行愈远的背影，宋集薪收回恶狠狠的眼神后，跳下墙头，似乎记起什么，对陈平安说道：“你还记得正月里的那条四脚吗？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T104559Z">
        <seg>After glaring at the departing figures of the young boy and the old man for a while, Song Jixin withdrew his gaze with a resentful expression before jumping down from the wall. A thought then suddenly seemed to have occurred to him, and he turned to Chen Ping'an as he asked, "Do you still remember that four leg from last month?"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>汉子咧嘴，露出一嘴参差不齐的大黄牙，嘿嘿笑道：“所以啊，如果不想以后变成我这样的光棍，就别惦记那五文钱。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T070629Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T070629Z">
        <seg>"That's exactly right! If you don't want to end up like me, then forget about those five copper coins," the gatekeeper chuckled, grinning to reveal a mouthful of crooked yellow teeth.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>汉子恼羞成怒，将事先准备好的五枚铜钱，狠狠拍在少年手心后，大手一挥，豪气干云道：“剩下五钱，先欠着！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T172537Z">
        <seg>The gatekeeper pulled out the five copper coins that he had prepared earlier in a disgruntled fashion before slamming them heavily down onto the palm of Chen Ping'an's hand, then gave him a dismissive wave as he said, "I'll give you the remaining five copper coins some other time!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>汉子愕然，低头看着少年，一本正经道：“你小子，是真傻。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T171814Z">
        <seg>The gatekeeper was rather taken aback by this innocent response, and he turned to Chen Ping'an with a serious expression as he said, "You really are a stupid kid."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>汉子抬头笑骂道：“老子还需要你来教训？年轻人阳气壮，屁股上能烙饼！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T071605Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T071416Z">
        <seg>The gatekeeper raised his head as he scoffed, "I don't need you to teach me where to sit! I'm a healthy and hot-blooded young man! You could even cook a pancake on my ass!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>汉子有些吃瘪，神色恼火，挥手赶人：“滚滚滚，跟你小子聊天真费劲。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T071309Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T071309Z">
        <seg>The gatekeeper was rather disgruntled by that irrefutable argument, and he waved a dismissive hand to chase Chen Ping'an away. "Piss off! Talking to you is like talking to a damn wall!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>汉子看破少年心思，笑得更加开心，“你要是不傻，老子能让你来送信？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T171320Z">
        <seg>The gatekeeper could tell what Chen Ping'an was thinking, and he began to laugh even more boisterously. "If you aren't stupid, I wouldn't have asked you to come deliver letters!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>汉子转头瞥了眼少年的背影，歪歪嘴，嘀咕了一句，好像是骂老天爷的丧气话。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T071716Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T071716Z">
        <seg>The gatekeeper took a glance at the departing Chen Ping'an out of the corner of his eye, then pursed his lips as he mumbled something, seemingly cursing the heavens.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>汉子转过头，望向那些人，伸手揉着胡里拉碴的下巴，低声啧啧道：“刚才那婆娘，两条腿能夹死人啊。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T171700Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T171700Z">
        <seg>The gatekeeper turned and cast his gaze toward the outsiders, stroking his stubbly chin as he mused to himself, "That woman just now had a pair of killer legs!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>没有让他失望，古塔上浮现着金色的文字，乃是一篇无上功法，名为《不灭天经》，练到最高境界，身体便不坏不朽，与天地共存、与日月同寿！</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T073457Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T073313Z">
        <seg>Thankfully, he wasn't disappointed. A passage of golden text appeared on the ancient pagoda, containing a peerless cultivation art by the name of "Undying Heavenly Scripture". Upon reaching the highest level of the cultivation art, one would attain an indestructible and immortal body that would exist alongside heaven and earth for all of eternity!</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>没过多久，一只颜色可爱的小黄雀停到桃树枝头，喙啄犹嫩，轻轻嘶鸣。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T005745Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T005745Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>泥瓶巷家家户户的黄土院墙都很低矮，其实邻居少年完全不用踮起脚跟，就可以看到这边院子的景象，可每次跟陈平安说话，偏偏喜欢蹲在墙头上。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T100145Z">
        <seg>The earthen walls separating the homes in Clay Vase Valley were all very short, so the young boy could've easily looked over the wall to the other side, but he always liked to squat on top of the wall whenever he spoke to Chen Ping'an.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>浑身透着一股酸腐味的汉子转头，笑眯眯道：“小家伙，就你这种茅坑臭石头的脾气，将来很容易吃大亏的。难道没有听过一句老话，吃亏是福？你要是小亏也不愿意吃……”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T071050Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T070930Z">
        <seg>The gatekeeper's entire body was giving off a sour and rotten odor, and he grinned as he said, "If you keep up that stinky attitude of yours, there's a very good chance that you're going to get in big trouble in the future. Have you not heard the saying that suffering a loss is a blessing? If you're not willing to suffer even minor losses..."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>温文尔雅的儒士隐约露出一抹怒容，缓缓转头望去。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T082916Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T082916Z">
        <seg>A hint of anger appeared on Mr. Qi's face, and he slowly turned away with a cold look in his eyes.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>然后宋集薪邀功一般，抬头笑问道：“对吧，齐先生？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T074907Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T074907Z">
        <seg>He then looked up with a smile as if he were searching for praise and asked, "Isn't that right, Mr. Qi."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>牵着男孩的中年妇人，轻轻咳嗽了一下，孩子这才稍稍收敛。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T170041Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T170041Z">
        <seg>The middle-aged woman holding onto the boy's hand cleared her throat quietly, and only then did the boy display some restraint.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>用宋集薪的话说就是天生穷苦命，哪怕有福气进了家门，他陈平安也兜不住留不下。宋集薪经常说一些晦涩难懂的话语，约莫是从书籍上搬来的内容，陈平安总是听不太懂，例如前两天念叨什么料峭春寒冻杀少年，陈平安就完全不明白，至于每年熬过了冬天，入春之后有段时日反而更冷，少年倒是切身体会，宋集薪说那就叫倒春寒，跟沙场上的回马枪一样厉害，所以很多人会死在这些个鬼门关上。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T134458Z">
        <seg>In Song Jixin's words, Chen Ping'an was destined to lead an impoverished life, and even if the winds of fortune were to blow into his home, he wouldn't be able to keep it anyway. Song Jixin often said some things that were very difficult to understand. He most likely took those esoteric sayings from the books that he read, and Chen Ping'an was often left scratching his head in befuddlement. For example, a few days ago, Song Jixin had been saying something something along the lines of "beware of the spring chill, for it has been the death of many a young man", and Chen Ping'an had no idea what that meant. However, he had first-hand experience of the strange phenomenon where the initial period of spring felt colder than the winter each year. Song Jixin referred to this phenomenon as the unexpected spring chill, which caught many people off guard before claiming their lives, much like a sudden and unforeseen retaliation from an opponent on the battlefield.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>男人笑了笑，善解人意道：“无妨，道理全在书上，做人却在书外。你去忙吧。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021035Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T020847Z">
        <seg>The man gave a considerate smile as he said, "It's alright. The knowledge is all in the books, but the way to be a good person is something that needs to be learned outside of books. You can go now."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>男孩比陈平安要矮大半个脑袋，孩子跟他擦身而过的时候，张了张嘴，虽然并没有发出声响，但是有明显的口型，应该是说了两个字，充满了挑衅。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T170020Z">
        <seg>The boy was almost a full head shorter then Chen Ping'an, and as he by Chen Ping'an, he opened his mouth, but didn't say anything. However, it was quite apparent that he had mouthed something very rude and provocative.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>留到最后的那封信，陈平安需要送去给乡塾授业的教书先生，期间路过一座算命摊子，是个身穿老旧道袍的年轻道士，挺直腰杆坐镇桌后，他头戴一顶高冠，像一朵绽放的莲花。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T010532Z">
        <seg>The final letter that Chen Ping'an had to deliver was addressed to the teacher at the private school. Along the way, he passed by a fortune teller's stall, where a young taoist priest in an old taoist robe was seated behind a table with his back ramrod straight. He was wearing a tall hat that resembled a blooming lotus flower.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>白天自己无意间看到有个中年人，提着只鱼篓走在大街上，捕获了一尾巴掌长短的金黄鲤鱼，它在竹篓里蹦跳得厉害，陈平安只瞥了一眼，就觉得很喜庆，于是开口询问，能不能用十钱买下它，中年人本来只是想着犒劳犒劳自己的五脏庙，眼见有利可图，就坐地起价，狮子大开口，非要三十钱才肯卖。囊中羞涩的陈平安哪里有这么多闲钱，又实在舍不得那条金灿灿的鲤鱼，就眼馋跟着中年人，软磨硬泡，想着把价格砍到十五，哪怕是二十也行，就在中年人有松口迹象的时候，锦衣少年和高大老人正好路过，他们二话不说，用五十钱买走了鲤鱼和鱼篓，陈平安只能眼睁睁看着他们扬长而去，无可奈何。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T104303Z">
        <seg>Earlier in the day, he just so happened to spot a middle-aged man walking down the street while carrying a fish basket. He had caught a golden carp that was around the same length as a human hand, and it was flailing around vigorously in the bamboo basket. Chen Ping'an felt a sense of jubilation at the sight of the golden carp, and he asked the man if he was willing to sell the fish for 10 copper coins. The man had originally only intended to eat the fish, but he immediately jumped on the opportunity to make a profit from his catch, asking for an exorbitant price of 30 copper coins. The impoverished Chen Ping'an naturally didn't have that much spare money on his hands, but at the same time, he couldn't bear to leave the golden carp behind. Hence, he began to barter with the man, and he was willing to take the fish for 15 copper coins, even 20. Right as the man was beginning to show signs of relenting, the brocade-robed young boy and the old man just so happend to pass by, and they bought the carp and the fish basket for 50 copper coins without any hesitation, leaving Chen Ping'an to look on with a wistful expression.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>相比陈平安这个名字的粗浅俗气，邻居少年就要雅致许多，叫宋集薪，就连与他相依为命的婢女，也有个绉绉的称呼，稚圭。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T100910Z">
        <seg>The neighboring boy's name was Song Jixin, a name that was far more sophisticated compared with Chen Ping'an's shallow and tacky name. Even his personal maidservant, Zhi Gui, had a very elegant name. [ref]The Ping'an (平安) in Chen Ping'an's name literally translates to safety, so it's a pretty shallow and on-the-nose name, whereas Song Jixin and Zhi Gui's names don't have any particularly clear meanings, but the combination of characters used is a lot more elegant and sophisticated.[/ref]</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>看到这一幕后，原本叽叽喳喳像只小黄雀的小女孩，顿时没了煽风点火的兴致，转过头不再多看陈平安一眼，好像再多看一眼就会脏了她的眼睛。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T170743Z">
        <seg>The chattly little girl's enthusiasm was instantly snuffed out upon seeing this, and she turned away from Chen Ping'an without affording him so much as a second glance, as if looking at him would be an insult to her eyes.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>眼神冷漠。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T082916Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T082916Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>第1章 重生</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Yuanl" changedate="20230318T041925Z" creationid="Yuanl" creationdate="20230318T041925Z">
        <seg>Test</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>等他回过神，蒙学孩童正在摇头晃脑，按照先生的要求，娴熟背诵一段章：“惊蛰时分，天地生发，万物始荣。夜卧早行，广步于庭，君子缓行，以便生志”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T020539Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T020539Z">
        <seg>By the time he returned to his senses, he discovered that the children in the school were reciting a passage in a well-rehearsed manner as instructed by the teacher. "At the time of awakening, heaven and earth stirs, and all living things begin to flourish. Sleep late and wake early, take regular strolls, do so slowly, for good health and vitality."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>等到这行人远去，看门的汉子笑问道：“想不想知道他们说了什么？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T170958Z">
        <seg>After those people had faded into the distance, the gatekeeper turned to Chen Ping'an before asking, "Do you want to know what they said?"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>老人将那封家书轻轻放入袖子，没有着急回去宅院，抬头望向远方，视线浑浊。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T005432Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T005432Z">
        <seg>The old man gently tucked the letter into his sleeve, but instead of returning to his courtyard right away, he raised his head and cast a pair of slightly murky eyes into the distance.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>老人故意卖了一关子，眼见听众们无动于衷，根本不懂得捧场，只得继续说道：“说不定就隐匿在我们身边，道教神仙称之为潜龙在渊！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230436Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T230340Z">
        <seg>The old man intentionally paused here to try and build some suspense, but the audience remained unmoved, completely oblivious to what he was doing, so he could only continue, "Perhaps they're hidden right among us! The deities of taoism refer to them as dragons lurking in plain sight!" </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>老人笑呵呵道：“别急别急，等到了水井边上坐下来，再给你看个够。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T093039Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T092916Z">
        <seg>"Don't be in such a hurry. Let me take a seat on the edge of the well, and I'll let you look as much as you want," the old man chuckled.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>老人转身离去。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T005744Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T005744Z">
        <seg>The old man turned to depart, and shortly thereafter, a small oriole with adorable colors landed on the tip of one of the peach trees' branches, chirping gently as it did so. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>老先生说得唾沫四溅，底下所有小镇百姓都无动于衷，人人满脸茫然。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T212041Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T212041Z">
        <seg>The old man was speaking with such vigor and enthusiasm that spittle was flying everywhere out of his mouth, but all of the town residents around him were looking on with lost and befuddled expressions.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>老者的视线在陈平安一扫而过，并无停滞，但是在宋集薪和婢女身上，多有停留，笑意渐渐浓郁。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T101420Z">
        <seg>His gaze swept over Chen Ping'an without any pause, but his attention lingered on Song Jixin and his maidservant, and the smile on his face gradually grew more pronounced.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>而且都是陌生人，小镇当地百姓的进进出出，无论是去烧瓷还是做庄稼活，都很少走东门，理由很简单，小镇东门的道路延伸出去，没有什么龙窑和田地。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T150452Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T150447Z">
        <seg>Furthermore, they were all unfamiliar to him. The local residents very rarely went through the eastern gate, regardless of whether they were tending to their fields or going to their kilns. The reason for this was very simple: the path leading out of the town's eastern gate didn't lead to any kilns or plots of farmland.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>而他的爹娘，走得早。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T070122Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T070122Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>至于写了什么，陈平安茫然不知。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T014212Z">
        <seg>As for what had been written, Chen Ping'an had no clue.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>草鞋少年身形矫健，快速横移一步，想要拦截下这片树叶。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230750Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T230750Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an was quite agile, and he quickly took a step to the side to try and intercept the leaf, but it continued to evade him as it twirled around in the air.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>虽然姚老头性子孤僻，不近人情，动辄打骂陈平安，曾经有一次，姚老头嫌弃陈平安悟性太差，简直就是个不开窍的蠢货，一气之下就把他丢在荒郊野岭，老人独自返回窑口。等到少年走了六十里山路，临近那座龙窑的时候，已是深夜时分，那天大雨滂沱，当在泥泞中蹒跚而行的少年，终于遥遥看到一点光亮的时候，倔强少年在独力讨生活后，第一次有想哭的冲动。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T063942Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T063942Z">
        <seg>Old Man Yao was a loner who could be quite inhumane at times, often beating and insulting Chen Ping'an. There was one time when Old Man Yao became so disgusted by how little talent and aptitude Chen Ping'an had that he abandoned him in the wilderness in a fit of rage before returning to the kiln alone. By the time Chen Ping'an navigated the 60 kilometers of mountain terrain back to the dragon kiln, it was already very late at night. It had been raining heavily that day, and after finally spotting a hint of light in the distance after trudging through the mud for hours, the stubborn and resilient Chen Ping'an was struck by the urge to cry for the first time.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>虽然这辈子都未必用得着这门手艺，但陈平安仍是像以往一般，闭上眼睛，想象自己身前搁置有青石板和轱辘车，开始练习拉坯，熟能生巧。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T094034Z">
        <seg>Even though there was a chance that Chen Ping'an would never use this skill again, he still performed his usual routine, closing his eyes and envisioning a bluestone slab and a pottery wheel in front of himself. He then began to simulate pottery molding practice, continuing to hone his skills.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>要知道陈平安虽然看着孱弱，但力气不容小觑，这是少年那些年烧瓷拉坯锻炼出来的身体底子，除此之外，陈平安还跟着姓姚的老人，跑遍了小镇方圆百里的山山水水，尝遍了四周各种土壤的滋味，任劳任怨，什么脏活累活都愿意做，毫不拖泥带水。可惜老姚始终不喜欢陈平安，嫌弃少年没有悟性，是榆木疙瘩不开窍，远远不如大徒弟刘羡阳，这也怪不得老人偏心，师父领进门，修行在个人，例如同样是枯燥乏味的拉坯，刘羡阳短短半年的功力，就抵得上陈平安辛苦三年的水准。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T093800Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an had a rather frail appearance, but his strength was not to be underestimated. He had developed great physical conditioning from many years of pottery molding and firing, and in addition to that, he had traveled extensively with Old Man Yao, exploring all types of places while carrying out the most tiresome and degrading tasks without any complaints. Unfortunately, despite his efforts, Old Man Yao never took a liking to him. He always disdainful toward Chen Ping'an for his lack of talent, an area in which he was severely outmatched by Old Man Yao's eldest disciple. Liu Xianyang. One couldn't blame the old man for playing favorites. Ultimately, the master was only responsible for teaching the basics, while the disciple's talent and hard work decided how far they would go. As an example of their disparity in talent, Liu Xianyang was able to achieve the same level of mastery in the monotonous task of pottery molding in half a year as Chen Ping'an did after toiling away for three years.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>许久过后，儒士叹了口气。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T090450Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T090450Z">
        <seg>Some time later, the scholar heaved a faint sigh.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>说是宝甲，陈平安亲眼看过一次，其实模样丑陋，既像是人身上的瘊子，也像是老树的疤结。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T124207Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T124207Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an had seen this supposed prized suit of aromr once, and it was extremely hideous, like a suit of warts, or like scarred and mottled surface of an old tree.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>走到自家屋前，发现院门大开，以为遭贼的少年连忙跑入院子，结果看到一个高大少年坐在门槛上，背靠上锁的屋门，百无聊赖地打着哈欠，看到陈平安后，火烧屁股一般站起身，跑到陈平安身前，一把攥紧陈平安的胳膊，狠狠拽向屋子，压低嗓音道：“赶紧开门，有要紧事要跟你说！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T024702Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T024702Z">
        <seg>After returning to his home, he discovered that the gate of the courtyard was wide open. Thinking that he had just been robbed by a thief, Chen Ping'an hurriedly rushed inside, only to find a tall and broad young man sitting on the doorstep. He was leaning back against the locked door, yawning with a bored expression, and he immediately jumped to his feet at the sight of Chen Ping'an as if his bottom had just been scorched. He then rushed over to Chen Ping'an and grabbed tightly onto his arm before dragging him forcefully toward the room as he hissed in a low voice, "Open the door! I have something important to tell you!"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>踩在青石板上，跟踩在烂泥滩里，感觉是不太一样。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T203430Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T203430Z">
        <seg>It was definitely a different feeling stepping on bluestone slabs than soppy mud.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>转瞬之间，便有一只黄雀疾坠于桌面，低垂头颅，对着那枚铜钱轻轻一啄，之后它将其衔在嘴中，抬头望向年轻道人，黄雀眼眸灵动，与人无异。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T210137Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T210137Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>过了牌坊没多远，很快就看到一棵枝繁叶茂的老槐树，树底下，有一根不知被谁挪来此地的树干，略作劈砍后，首尾两端下边，垫着两块青石板，这截大树便被当做了简易的长凳。每年夏天的时候，小镇百姓都喜欢在这边乘凉，家境富裕的人家，长辈还会从水井里捞出一篮子的冰镇瓜果，孩子们吃饱喝足，就拉帮结派，在树荫下嬉戏打闹。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T145108Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T145108Z">
        <seg>Shortly after passing the archway, he saw an old yet lush locust tree, and the foot of which was a tree trunk that had been moved there by someone. Slight modifications had been made to the tree trunk, and there were two bluestone slabs tucked under either end of it, transforming it into a crude bench. Every summer, all of the town's residents liked to gather under the tree to stay cool. Some of the adults from the wealthier families would pull baskets of chilled fruits and melons out of the well for the children to eat, and once they've had their fill of fruits, the children would band together and play under the shade of the tree.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>这一刻，宋集薪敏锐发现那老人，有意无意看了自己一眼，虽然只是蜻蜓点水的视线，很快就一掠而过，但宋集薪仍是细心捕捉到了，只是少年也就没有上心，只当是巧合而已。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T213114Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T213114Z">
        <seg>Right at this moment, Song Jixin noticed that the old man took a glance at him. It was unclear whether the glance was intentional or not, and it was only a very fleeting glance before his gaze was directed elsewhere, but Song Jixin was still sufficiently perceptive to have sensed it. However, he didn't think anything of it, merely chalking it up to a coincidence.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>这一挥袖，就有两支竹签从袖子里滑落，掉在地上，道人哎呦一声，赶紧捡起来，然后鬼鬼祟祟四处张望，发现暂时无人留心这边，这才如释重负，重新将那两支竹签藏入宽松的袖口。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T015254Z">
        <seg>As he rustled his sleeve, two bamboo slips fell out from witihn before clattering onto the ground. The taoist priest yelped in alarm as he hurriedly picked up the bamboo slips, then looked around in a sheepish manner and was very relieved to see that no one had caught sight of what had just happened. After that, he tucked the pair of bamboo slips back into his loose and baggy sleeve.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>这个背对着陈平安的男人，打开门后，时不时跟人收取一个小绣袋，放入自己袖口，然后一一放行。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T165546Z">
        <seg>His back was facing Chen Ping'an, and after opening the door, he would take a small embroidered pouch from each of the people outside, then stow the pouches up his sleeve before granting them passage into the town.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>这位先生微笑之时，让人如沐春风。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T082344Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T082244Z">
        <seg>The smile on his face made the beholder feel as if they were basking a warm spring breeze, and he suddenly said, "Go and pay Zhao Yao a visit. It'll be an early farewell."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>这位教书先生犹豫片刻，终于还是开口说道：“无需为我送行。宋集薪，你以后到了小镇之外，记得不要太过张扬。我身无别物，三本蒙学书籍，《小学w，《礼乐w，《观止w，你可以一并拿去，经常温习，需知读书百遍，其义自见。若是能读书破万卷，更是下笔如有神，此间真意……你以后自然会知晓的。至于三本闲杂书，术算《精微w，棋谱《桃李w，文集《山海策w，不妨闲暇时翻阅，也可怡情养性。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T082003Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T082003Z">
        <seg>The scholar hesitated momentarily, then said, "There's no need to do that. After you leave the town, make sure to keep a low profile and not draw attention to yourself. I don't have anything other than three elementary books, namely 'Principles of Life for Children', 'Rites and Music', and 'An Anthology of Literary Essays'. You can take them all. Make sure to revise them regularly. Only by repeatedly reading a book over and over again will you be able to glean its true meaning. If you can read over 10,000 books, you'll be able to write as if you were assisted by the gods. You'll understand what that means when you get to that point. As for those three light readings, 'Profound and Subtle', 'Tao Li Anthology', and 'Tales of Mountains and Seas', I encourage you to read them in your free time as well for self-cultivation."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>远处算命摊子那边，年轻道人闭目养神，自言自语道：“是谁说天运循环无厚薄？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T231114Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T231114Z">
        <seg>Over at the fortune telling stall in the distance, the young taoist priest murmured to himself, "Who says there's disparity in the cycle of fortune?"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>远处陈平安的脚步，明显停顿了一下，年轻道人已经火速起身，趁热打铁，高声道：“大早上的，年轻人你是头位客人，贫道干脆就好人做到底，只要你坐下抽签，实不相瞒，贫道会写一些黄纸符，可以帮你为先人祈福，积攒阴德，以贫道的能耐，不敢说一定让人投个大富大贵的好胎，可要说多出一两分福报，终归是尝试一下的。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T011515Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an had already jogged into the distance at this point, but he clearly faltered slightly in his footsteps. The young taoist priest instantly jumped on the opportunity, quickly rising to his feet as he declared, "It's still very early in the morning, so you'll be my first customer, young man. In light of that, I'll do you an additional favor. If you sit down for a reading, I'll write up some yellow paper talismans for you and help you pray to your ancestors so you can accumulate some good karma. With my skills, I wouldn't dare to guarantee that you'll be reincarnated into a wealthy family in your next life, but I can certainly try and bless you with a bit of good fortune."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>远处，宋集薪高声喊道：“稚圭，回家啦。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T085345Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T085345Z">
        <seg>In the distance, Song Jixin called out, "Time to go home, Zhi Gui."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>道人匆忙接住铜钱，摊开手心一看，愁眉不展，才是最小额的一钱。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T210010Z">
        <seg>The taoist priest hurriedly caught the coin before spreading his hand open and taking a look, only to discover that it was smallest money value copper coin possible, and his mood wasn't lifted at all.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>道人哈哈笑道：“万一抽出上上签，可不就是五钱了嘛。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T013151Z">
        <seg>"But it'll be five copper coins if you manage to pull the best slip," the taoist priest chuckled.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>道人微微睁开一丝眼缝，眼见着又要错过生意，只得一巴掌拍在桌案上，提高嗓门，“状元本是人间子，宰相无非世上人。学贯天人名动城，得意扬扬精气神！”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T205638Z">
        <seg>The taoist priest opened his eyes ever so slightly, and seeing that more potential customers were about to pass him by, he hurriedly slammed a palm down onto his table as he raised his voice and continued, "Champion scholars and prime ministers were nothing more than normal people before their rise to glory. With great knowledge comes great renown and confidence."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>道人微笑道：“年轻人，不要紧张，命里有时终须有，命里无时莫强求，以平常心看待无常事，便是第一等万全法。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T013554Z">
        <seg>The taoist priest smiled as he said, "Don't be nervous, young man. If it's meant to be, then it'll be. If it's not meant to be, then it can't be forced. Regarding impermanence with a peaceful heart is the solution to everything."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>道人悠悠然念完这句诗词后，故作潇洒地轻轻挥袖，叹气道：“命里八尺，莫求一丈啊。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T015140Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T015140Z">
        <seg>After casually reciting that poem phrase to himself, he rustled his sleeve in a carefree manner as he sighed, "If it's not meant to be, then there's no point in forcing things."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>道人懒洋洋靠在椅子上，瞥了眼铜钱，弯腰伸手将它们搂到身前。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T014533Z">
        <seg>The taoist priest sat back lazily in his chair, then took a glance at the copper coins before bending over and scooping them close to him.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>道人显然吓得不轻，起身后也顾不得摊子了，抱头鼠窜。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T204351Z">
        <seg>The taoist priest was clearly very much intimidated by this threat, and he immediately turned and fled, leaving his stall behind.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>道人正襟危坐，“贫道看人福气厚薄，财运多寡，一向很准。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T013409Z">
        <seg>The taoist priest replied with a serious expression, "I can see if someone is blessed by fortune or not, and in particular, I've always been very accurate when it comes to my readings of one's fortune in wealth."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>道人灰心丧气，低声咕哝道：“这日子没法过了。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T205836Z">
        <seg>The taoist priest was greatly disheartened by this, and he murmured to himself, "It's over."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>道人犹不死心，身体前倾，提高嗓门，“年轻人，往日贫道替人解签，要收十钱，今儿破个例，只收你三钱！当然了，若是抽出了一支上签，你不妨再多加一喜钱，如果鸿运当头，是上上签，那贫道也只收你五钱，如何？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T010937Z">
        <seg>The taoist priest was unwilling to give up, and he leaned forward slightly as he raised his voice and continued, "How about this, young man? I normally charge 10 copper coins for a reading, but today, I'll make an exception and only charge you three copper coins! Of course, if you pick out a good slip, you're free to pay a little extra for good fortune. Even if you're fortunate enough to pick out the best slip possible, I'll only charge you five copper coins. What do you say?"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>道人笑意如常，略作思量，点头道：“可。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T014032Z">
        <seg>The taoist priest's smile remained unchanged, and after some thought, he nodded in response. "Sure."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>道人笑着伸出手，示意少年拿起签筒。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T011736Z">
        <seg>The taoist priest smiled as he extended a hand, inviting Chen Ping'an to pick up the tube of bamboo slips.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>道人轻声道：“去吧，此地不宜久留。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T210151Z">
        <seg>The taoist priest sighed, "Go. This is not the place for you."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>那一刻，穿着自编草鞋的少年，只是有些羡慕那些人身上的厚实衣衫，肯定很暖和，能挨冻。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T150713Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an was wearing a pair of straw sandals woven by himself, and he was very envious of the thick clothing worn by the people outside. In his eyes, the clothes looked very warm and were sure to be great for keeping out the cold.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>那对少年少女显然听到了道人的话语，只可惜没有要停步的意思。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T205333Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T205333Z">
        <seg>The pair of youths passing by clearly heard him, but unfortunately, they displayed no intention of stopping.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>那少年微笑道：“那你说个价。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T101645Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T101645Z">
        <seg>"How much do you want for her?" the brocade-robed young boy asked with a faint smile.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>锦衣少年不再理睬宋集薪，偏移视线，望向陈平安，“今天多亏了你，我才能买到那条鲤鱼，买回去后，我越看越欢喜，想着一定要当面跟你道一声谢，于是就让吴爷爷带我连夜来找你。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T102407Z">
        <seg>The young boy paid no further heed to Song Jixin as he turned to his gaze to Chen Ping'an. "It's all thanks to you that I was able to buy that carp today. After taking it back home, the more I looked at it, the more I fell in love with it, so I decided that I had to come and thank you in person. That's why I asked Grandpa Wu to bring me here to see you right away."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>锦衣少年嘴角翘起，道：“逗你玩的。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T101943Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T101943Z">
        <seg>An amused smile appeared on the boy's face as he said, "I was just fooling around."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>锦衣少年脸色如常，点头道：“好。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T101854Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T101854Z">
        <seg>The brocade-robed young boy's expression remained unchanged as he nodded in response. "Alright, I'll take her."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>锦衣少年身边站着一位身材高大的老者，面容白皙，脸色和蔼，轻轻眯眼打量着两座毗邻院落的少年少女。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T101412Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T101412Z">
        <seg>Beside the brocade-robed young boy stood a tall and broad elderly man with a fair complexion and a benevolent look on his face. The old man's eyes were slightly narrowed as his gaze roamed over the young trio in the two neighboring courtyards.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>门外那些人，明显分作好几拨，并不是一伙人，但都望向门内的清瘦少年，大多脸色漠然，偶有一两人，视线早已越过少年的身影，望向小镇更远处。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T150840Z">
        <seg>The people outside the town gate were clearly split up into several groups, rather than belonging to one large group, but all of them wore aloof and indifferent expressions as they looked at Chen Ping'an. A couple of them had already looked past him and were peering further into the town.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安一手拿信，一手摊开手掌，眨了眨眼睛，“说好了一封信一钱的。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T172333Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an grabbed the letters with one hand while spreading open his other hand, blinking innocently as he said, "You promised me one copper coin per letter."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安下定决心，伸手去拿签筒，突然抬头问道：“道长是如何知道我身上恰好有五钱？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T013227Z">
        <seg>After making up his mind, Chen Ping'an reached out for the slip tube, only to suddenly raise his head as he asked, "How did you know that I just so happen to have exactly five copper coins on me?"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安习惯了上山下水，跑到栅栏门口附近，在那座孤零零的黄泥房门口停下，心不跳气不喘。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T145211Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an was already accustomed to rigorous travel, so he wasn't even out of breath as he jogged over to the makeshift town gate before stopping at the entrance of the earthen cabin.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安低声反驳道：“是三钱。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T013126Z">
        <seg>"It's thee copper coins," Chen Ping'an argued in a low voice.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安刚想要说话，锦衣少年已经转身离去。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T102900Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an was just about to say something, but the brocade-robed young boy had already departed, leaving Chen Ping'an to look on with furrowed brows.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安反驳道：“我方才不是说了，不要五文钱吗？难道不算吃小亏？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T071155Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T071155Z">
        <seg>"Didn't I just say I could do without the five copper coins? Is that not accepting a minor loss?" Chen Ping'an retorted.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安叹了口气，“路上小心。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T105916Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an heaved a faint sigh in response. "Look after yourselves."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安叹了口气，抬起头，认真道：“你要是手头紧，这五文钱就算了吧，可是事先说好，以后一封信一颗铜钱，不能再赖账的。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T070805Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T070805Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an heaved a faint sigh as he raised his head and said in a serious manner, "If you're a little tight on money right now, then I can do without the five copper coins, but we agreed upon one copper coin per letter, so you can't keep refusing to pay me like this."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安坐在长凳上，静待下。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T111946Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T111946Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an sat down on the bench, waiting for Liu Xianyang to finish.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安坐在门槛上，揉了揉额头，这个宋集薪，其实不说那些怪话胡话的时候，给人感觉并不差，但是比如这种时候，刘羡阳在场的话，就一定会说他很想朝宋集薪的后脑勺，一板砖敲下去。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T203116Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T203116Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an sat down on his doorstep as he rubbed his own forehead in exasperation. When he wasn't talking nonsense, Song Jixin actually wasn't a bad person to be around. However, at times like this, if Liu Xianyang were here, he would've definitely expressed to Chen Ping'an an urge to smash a brick into the back of Song Jixin's head.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安好奇问道：“刘羡阳，你在干什么？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T030734Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T030734Z">
        <seg>"What are you doing, Liu Xianyang?" Chen Ping'an asked with a curious expression.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安实在听不下去了，打断刘羡阳的话语，“宋集薪对她不坏的。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T113052Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T113052Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an couldn't bear to listen in silence any longer, and he interjected, "Song Jixin doesn't treat her badly."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安将书信双手递出去，恭敬道：“这是先生的书信。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T020644Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an offered the letter to him with both hands as he said in a respectful voice, "I have a letter for you, Sir."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安小跑路过杏花巷的时候，看到不少妇人孩子聚在铁锁井旁，水井轱辘一直在吱呀作响。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T135233Z">
        <seg>While jogging past Apricot Blossom Alley, Chen Ping'an spotted many women and children huddled around the Iron Lock Well, and the well winch was creaking incessantly.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安很早就让出道路，八个人大致分作五批，走向小镇，除了那个头戴高冠、腰悬绿佩的年轻人，还先后走过两个七八岁的孩子，男孩穿着一件颜色喜庆的红色袍子，女孩长得粉粉嫩嫩，跟上好瓷器似的。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T165908Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an had already stepped aside to let the people through, and eight outsiders made their way into the town, roughly split up into five groups. Two children who were around seven or eight years of age strode into the town on either side of the young man with the green jade pendant strapped to his waist. The pair of children consisted of a boy and a girl, and the former was wearing a festive red robe, while the little girl was as fair and delicate as a piece of premium porcelain.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安想了想，拿起那只签筒。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T013431Z">
        <seg>After a brief moment of contemplation, Chen Ping'an picked up the slip tube.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安想了想，蹲在门槛旁边，低头吹散那些灰烬。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T130714Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T130714Z">
        <seg>After some contemplation, Chen Ping'an crouched down beside his doorstep and lowered his head to blow away the ashes.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安愣了愣，将信将疑地转身返回，坐在摊子前的长凳上。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T011547Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an faltered slightly upon hearing this, then turned back around with a skeptical expression before taking a seat on the bench in front of the stall.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安扯了扯嘴角，心想你当我傻啊？</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T171312Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an gave a wry smile in response. 

Do I look stupid to you? qhetiqhewithoiwhtoiwhethewhtiowhethewthewothoewit</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安抬头望去，旭日东升，煌煌泱泱。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T015940Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T015940Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安抬起头。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T113630Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T113630Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an raised his upon hearing this.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安抬起头，“不去了。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T202416Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T202416Z">
        <seg>"I'll pass," Chen Ping'an replied as he raised his head.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安摇了摇头。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T110021Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an shook his head.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安撒开腿跑去送最后一封信。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T014433Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T014433Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安收回视线，穿街过巷，一路小跑向小镇东面，泥瓶巷在小镇西边，最东边的城门，有个人负责小镇商旅进出和夜禁巡防，平时也收取、转交一些从外边寄回来的家书，陈平安接下来要做的事情，就是把那些信送给小镇百姓，酬劳是一封信一枚铜钱，这还是他好不容易求来的挣钱门路，陈平安已经跟那边约好，在二月二龙抬头之后，就开始接手这摊子买卖。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T114042Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an withdrew his gaze as he jogged through a series of streets and alleys toward the eastern side of the small town. Clay Vase Valley was situated in the westernmost part of the town, and at the town gate on the easternmost part of the town was a man who was responsible for conducting nightly patrols and overseeing the merchants and visitors entering the exiting the town. On the side, he would also receive and transfer some letters sent to the town, and Chen Ping'an's job was to take those letters and deliver them to the town's residents for one copper coin per letter. This was an avenue of income that he had gone to great lengths to obtain, and it had already been arranged that he was going to be taking over this job after the day of the Longtaitou Festival.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安放下新折的那根桃枝，吹灭蜡烛，走出屋子后，坐在台阶上，仰头望去，星空璀璨。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T084410Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an set down the newly snapped peach branch before blowing out the candle. He then made his way out of the room and sat down on the steps before looking up at the starry night sky.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安放缓脚步，屋内响起中年人的醇厚嗓音，“日出有曜，羔裘如濡。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T015853Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T015853Z">
        <seg>He slowed down outside the school, and the mellow voice of a middle-aged man rang out from inside. "The radiant sun shines down upon the pristine woollen coat."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安斜靠着屋门，想着明天的光景，多半会像今天，后天的光景，则会像明天，如此反复，于是他陈平安这辈子就会一直这样走下去，直到最后跟姚老头差不多。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T203239Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T203239Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an leaned against his doorframe as he thought about what the next day was going to be like. It was most likely going to be just like this day, and the day after the next day was going to be just like the next day. In his mind, he was going to live out his life in this repetitive cycle until he passed away just like Old Man Yao.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安有些为难，毕竟他未必真有时间来此听这位先生教书，少年不愿欺骗他。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T020747Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an was reluctant to make any promises. He couldn't guarantee that he would have the time to come and listen to these lessons, and he didn't want to lie to the teacher.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安有些奇怪，难道这些人还不知道朝廷已经封禁了所有龙窑？还是说他们正因为知道真相，所以觉得有机可乘？</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T150926Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an was rather perplexed to see this. Could it be that these people weren't aware that the imperial court had already shut down all of the dragon kilns in the village? Alternatively, could it be that they felt like there was an opportunity to be exploited here because they knew the true reason for the closure of the kilns?</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安来到东门，看到那汉子盘腿坐在栅栏门口的树墩上，懒洋洋晒着初春的日头，闭着眼睛，哼着小曲，双手拍打膝盖。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T231726Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T231726Z">
        <seg>Upon arriving at the eastern gate, Chen Ping'an spotted the gatekeepr sitting on the tree stump at the gate with his legs crossed, lazily basking under the early spring sun. His eyes were closed, and he was humming a tune while patting his knees with his hands.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安松了口气，告辞离去。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T020857Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an heaved a faint sigh of relief before taking his leave.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安松开手指，丢了泥土，起身后说道：“树墩子潮气重……”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T071500Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T071348Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an released the handful of dirt, then stood up as he said, "Tree stumps are really damp, you're going to get rheumatism from sitting on that thing."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安根本听不懂女孩在说什么，不过猜得出，她是在告状。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T170235Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an couldn't understand anything that she was saying, but he could tell that she was complaining about the boy.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安没敢反驳，生怕惹恼了这家伙，即将到手的铜钱就要飞走了。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T171609Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an didn't dare to rebuke the gatekeeper for fear of irking him and losing this job.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安没有停下脚步，不过转过头，摆摆手。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230352Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T010753Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an continued to jog past without pause, but he turned to the taoist priest and waved a hand in refusal.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安没能挣脱开这家伙的束缚，只得被他拉去开了屋门，比他年龄年长两岁的健壮少年，很快就摔开陈平安，蹑手蹑脚摸上陈平安的木板床，将耳朵死死贴在墙壁上，听起了隔壁的墙脚根。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T030601Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T030601Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an was unable to struggle free and could only allow himself to be dragged to the door. The young man was two years older than Chen Ping'an and more physically developed, and after the door was opened, he quickly threw Chen Ping'an aside before sneaking his way onto Chen Ping'an's plank bed, then pressed his ear tightly against the wall to eavesdrop on the neighbors.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安没附和高大少年的说法。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T112744Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T112744Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an didn't echo Liu Xianyang's sentiment.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安满脸无奈，“你不就在计较吗？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T070542Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T070542Z">
        <seg>"Aren't you being petty here?" Chen Ping'an countered with an exasperated expression.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安点了点头。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T123359Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T104604Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an nodded in response, and Liu Xianyang departed from Clay Vase Alley.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安点头道：“想啊。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T171006Z">
        <seg>"I do," Chen Ping'an replied with a nod.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安犹豫不决，突然说道：“我不抽签，你只帮我写一份黄纸符，行不行？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T011809Z">
        <seg>However, Chen Ping'an didn't hesitate even for a moment as he declared, "I don't want to draw a slip. All I want is for you to write up a yellow paper talisman for me. Can you do that?"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安犹豫了一下，好奇问道：“那位夫人练过武？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T171743Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an hesitated momentarily before asking with an intrigued expression, "Is she a martial arts practitioner?"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安猛然起身，正要道一声谢。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T114148Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T114148Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an immediately stood up, and he was just about to express his gratitude when Liu Xianyang raised a hand to cut him off. "Stop! No need to thank me, just remember what I've done for you."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安的眼角余光，无意间发现年轻人身后的那些人，好像有人失望，有人玩味，有人皱眉，有人讥讽，情绪微妙，各不相同。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T163848Z">
        <seg>Out of his peripheral vision, Chen Ping'an inadvertently noticed that the people behind the young man seemed to all be displaying different emotions. Some were disappointed, some were amused, some had their brows furrowed, and some were looking on with derision in their eyes.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安皱了皱眉头。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T102902Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T102902Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安看着那个高大背影。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T115642Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T115642Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an looked on at his departing figure, and all of a sudden, Liu Xianyang turned around to face Chen Pingan again.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安眼神清澈，轻声道：“有些时候她在院子里做事，宋集薪偶尔坐在板凳上，看他那本什么地方县志，她看宋集薪的时候，经常会笑。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T113322Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T113322Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an's eyes were bright and clear as he said, "Sometimes, when she's doing things in the yard, Song Jixin would occasionally read that Local County Chronicles book while sitting on a stool, and she would often look at him and smile."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安站在学塾门口，欲言又止。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T020558Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an was standing at the entrance of the school, and he wanted to say something, but refrained from doing so.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安继续去往城东门，哪怕要不到钱，催一催也是好的。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230933Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T230933Z">
        <seg>Meanwhile, Chen Ping'an continued on toward the eastern town gate. Even if he couldn't get the money, it was always definitely a good idea to exert some pressure on the gatekeeper.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安翻了个白眼，对这些尖酸刻薄的言语，少年并不以为意，一来生活在这座总共没几本书籍的乡野地方，如果被人骂几句就恼火，干脆找口水井跳下去得了，省心省事。二来这个看门的中年光棍，本身就是个经常被小镇百姓取笑打趣的对象，尤其是那些胆大泼辣的妇人，别说嘴上骂他，动手打他的都有不少。加上这人还极其喜欢跟穿开裆裤的小孩吹牛，比如什么老子当年在城门口，好一场厮杀，打得五六个大汉满地找牙，满地都是血，城门前整条两丈宽的道路，就跟下雨天的泥泞道路差不多！</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T165308Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an rolled his eyes in response, completely unfazed by the man's scathing words. He was living in a rural area filled with uneducated people, if he allowed himself to get mad everytime someone directed some insults at him, then he may as well jump into a well and put himself out of his misery. In addition to that, this middle-aged gatekeeper was often the butt of jokes for the residents of the town himself. In particular, the bold and feisty women would not just verbally abuse him, but often hit him as well. The man was also always going around boasting to little kids who were still in their open crotch pants, telling them about how back in his heyday, he had once beaten up five or six burly men at once in front of the town gate, dishing out such a severe beating that his assailants were left to pick up their teeth from the ground, and that there was so much blood everywhere that the entire 20-foot wide path in front of the town gate had become as muddy as if it had just rained!</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安耐得住性子发呆，邋遢汉子好像觉得多半是没法子蒙混过关了，睁眼笑道：“不就五文钱嘛，男人这么小气，以后不会有大出息的。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T070526Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T070526Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an had the patience to stick around in silence, and it seemed that the gatekeeper could sense that he wouldn't be able to get out of this just by ignoring him. Hence, he opened his eyes and smiled as he said, "Get over it, it's just five copper coins! A young man shouldn't be so petty. Otherwise, you'll never make anything out of yourself."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安蹲在他身边，对于少年来说，讨债的事情，实在难以启齿。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T232048Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T232048Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an squatted down next to him. For him, it was very difficult to ask for the money that he was owed.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安蹲在地上，双头按住脑袋，唉声叹气，有些头疼。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T113504Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T113504Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an placed his hands onto his own head, squatting down as he heaved an exasperated sigh.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安这么多年，一直很羡慕刘羡阳。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T043922Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T043922Z">
        <seg>Over the years, Chen Ping'an had always been very envious of Liu Xianyang.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安送出去的第一封信，是祖上得到过一柄皇帝御赐玉如意的卢家，当少年站在门口，愈发局促不安。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T175648Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T175648Z">
        <seg>The first letter that he delivered was to the Lu Family, which had an ancestor that had received a jade scepter bestowed upon them by the emperor. As he stood outside the doors of the Lu Manor, he was becoming more and more agitated and uneasy.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安重新将签筒放回桌上，神情郑重，问道：“道长，我把五钱都给你，也不抽签了，只请道长将那张黄纸符，写得比平时更好一些，行不行？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T013701Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an set the tube slip back down onto the table, then asked with a serious expression, "How about this? I'll give you the five copper coins, and I won't draw a slip. All that I ask is that you write up the yellow paper talisman a bit better than you normally do. Is that possible?"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安问道：“是宋集薪学猫叫，还是稚圭？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T112105Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T112105Z">
        <seg>"Are you saying Song Jixin is imitating a cat? Or are you talking about Zhi Gui?" Chen Ping'an asked.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安默不作声。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T110211Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an offered no response to this.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>陈平安龇牙咧嘴。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T115337Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T114244Z">
        <seg>Chen Ping'an could only grimace in response.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>院门那边，有个嗓音响起，“你这婢女卖不卖？”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230318T101539Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T101020Z">
        <seg>All of a sudden, a voice rang out from the entrance of the courtyard. "Are you willing to sell that maidservant?"</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>随后便有一阵齐整清脆的稚嫩嗓音响起，“日出有曜，羔裘如濡。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T015921Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T015921Z">
        <seg>The phrase was immediately repeated in unison by a collection of tender voices. "The radiant sun shines down upon the pristine woollen coat."
</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>雨国，苍云镇凌家，月过中天。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Yuanl" changedate="20230318T041927Z" creationid="Yuanl" creationdate="20230318T041927Z">
        <seg>test</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>青衣少年赶紧起身，毕恭毕敬作揖告辞。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T080553Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T080553Z">
        <seg>The young boy hurriedly rose to his feet and extended a respectful bow before taking his leave.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>青衫少年不管如何不甘心，仍是缓缓投子。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T080217Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T080217Z">
        <seg>The azure-robed young boy was extremely reluctant to admit defeat, but he still resigned.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>青衫少年自己都不知道，肩头上不知何时停留一片槐叶。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T230856Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T230856Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>骤然间，单薄木板床支撑不住刘羡阳的重量，从中断成两半，高大少年一屁股坐在地面上。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T113422Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T113422Z">
        <seg>All of a sudden, the thin plank bed snapped in half down the middle, unable to support Liu Xianyang's weight any longer, and he sat heavily down onto the ground.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>高大少年对陈平安的问话置若罔闻，约莫半炷香后，刘羡阳恢复正常，坐在木板床边缘，脸色复杂，既有些释然，也有些遗憾。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T031029Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T031009Z">
        <seg>Liu Xianyang paid no heed to him, and after about seven or eight minutes, Liu Xianyang returned to normal before sitting down on the edge of the plank bed with a peculiar mixture of relief and disappointment on his face.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>魁梧老人斜瞥了一眼草鞋少年。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T021300Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230318T170342Z">
        <seg>The old man took a glance at Chen Ping'an out of the corner of his eye, and it was only a fleeting glance without any intention or malice, but Chen Ping'an reflexively took a step backward, as if he were a mouse that had run into a cat.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>黄雀一闪而逝。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230319T210158Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230319T210158Z">
        <seg>The oriole departed in a flash.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>齐先生坐在西面，一向观棋不语。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T072943Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T072943Z">
        <seg> </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>齐先生对弟子吩咐道：“练字去吧，不用收拾残局，写三百‘永’字。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T080534Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T080534Z">
        <seg>"Go and practice your calligraphy. There's no need to clean up the board. Write out the '永' character 300 times." [ref]The 永 is good for practicing the basics in calligraphy as it contains a series of fundamental strokes, as shown in this image: https://www.google.com/search?q=heng+shu+pie+na&amp;rlz=1C1JZAP_enAU984AU984&amp;sxsrf=AJOqlzVwrugXQMszg7aBgoqlQBnrZFGVCQ:1679299429224&amp;source=lnms&amp;tbm=isch&amp;sa=X&amp;ved=2ahUKEwib8szvher9AhWMFLcAHRiKB9sQ_AUoAXoECAEQAw&amp;biw=1366&amp;bih=657&amp;dpr=1#imgrc=f3lVaHi4COdbTM[/ref]</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>齐先生望向自己的学塾弟子，“你可以执白先行。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T075758Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T075758Z">
        <seg>Mr. Qi turned to his scholarly assistant and said, "You can go first with white."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>齐先生满脸笑意，柔声道：“没你说的这么夸张，人生何处不相逢，以后总有再见面的一天。”</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T082225Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T082225Z">
        <seg>A smile appeared on Mr. Qi's face as he said in a gentle voice, "It's not as serious as you make it out to be. Who knows where we'll meet again someday? I'm sure we'll be reunited eventually."</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="ZH-CN">
        <seg>齐先生语速不急不缓，仔细解释过了规矩后，并不繁琐，只是在四星位分别放下黑白两子。</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="EN-US" changeid="Admin" changedate="20230320T074433Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20230320T074433Z">
        <seg>Mr. Qi carefully explained the rules in an unhurried manner, and it wasn't very complicated. All that an even game entaile was placing down two black and white stones each on the four star points of the board.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
<!-- Alternative translations -->
  </body>
</tmx>
